<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?><exam id_exam="106R-3" title="Departamento de Idiomas. Escuela de Guerra | INGLÉS" fecha="EXAMEN COMPRENSION TEXTOS ABRIL 2013" tipo="Normal">
<intro1><![CDATA[En las sucesivas presentaciones usted encontrará preguntas de relacionadas con el texto redactado.]]></intro1>
<intro2><![CDATA[Después de leer y comprender el texto presentado deberá responder a una de las preguntas de la parte inferior.]]></intro2>
<intro3><![CDATA[Gracias por su colaboración. A continuación podrá <strong>imprimir</strong> las respuestas que han sido seleccionadas, o bien imprimirlas en un archivo <strong>pdf</strong> para su entrega al profesor correspondiente.]]></intro3>
<tiempoGlobal><![CDATA[75]]></tiempoGlobal>
<timeOver><![CDATA[Su tiempo ha terminado. Pulse finalizar e imprima sus respuestas]]></timeOver>
<user id= "1">LABRADO GOMEZ, CARLOS TIM: 51358887#</user>

<user id= "2">LAGUNA PEREZ, JAVIER TIM: 51652408#</user>

<user id= "3">CAP TOVAR HERNÁNDEZ, GERARDO TIM: 09279594#</user>

<user id= "4">MERINO TORO, LA BEGO TIM: 52104944#</user>

<user id= "5">TCOL. D. ANTONIO PIÑA SANCHEZ TIM: 43012165#</user>

<user id= "6">TCOL. D. ANGEL FERNANDEZ TUR TIM: 45068182#</user>

<user id= "7">T TE. D. ANDRES TORRES CASO TIM: 28800128#</user>

<user id= "8">CAP. ART.  JOSE  FRANCISCO   CAMPOS  BARBERO TIM: 06965997#</user>

<user id= "9">CAP. CAB.  GABRIEL     ECHEVERRIA  URQUIZU TIM: 15992562#</user>

<user id= "10">CAP. ABSTO.  MANUEL  JOSE    CEREZO       LOPEZ TIM: 30499977#</user>

<user id= "11">TCOL. D. GABRIEL AIZPURU DIAZ DE TERAN TIM: 17870902#</user>

<user id= "12">TCOL. JERÓNIMO DELGADO DE LUQUE TIM: 28683622#</user>

<user id= "13">COL. ALFONSO CHILLÓN MODREGO TIM: 17203922#</user>

<question nquest="1">
	<Text><![CDATA[Bill Richards.                                                                                        ………………………………Bill Richards gets up at 6am every day. He is never late for work. However, on Monday, he forgot to set his alarm clock. He woke up at 7am and arrived at the office an hour late. His boss was angry and warned him never to be late again.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[What is said about Bill Richards?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. He lost his job]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. He is usually late for work]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. He is forgetful]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. He was late on one occasion]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="2">
	<Text><![CDATA[Hero Saves Man’s Life.………………………………Jack Easton was driving home from work at 6.30 in the evening when he saw a yellow van, driven by James Smith, crash into a tree. Without thinking of his own safety, he pulled the young man out of the van and took him to hospital. James is making good progress.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[Which statement is true?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. Jack Easton crashed his car]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. James Smith will not recover]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. Jack Easton assisted James Smith]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. Jack Easton worried about his safety]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="3">
	<Text><![CDATA[Amount of Carbon Dioxide in Atmosphere will Delay Next Ice Age.  ………………………………It seems that the next Ice Age could be on hold because of the amount of carbon dioxide being released into the atmosphere by humans. The last Ice Age ended around 11,500 years ago and it had been predicted that the next one would begin in around 1,500 years. However, it is now thought that the amount of carbon dioxide in the atmosphere will delay this next Ice Age.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[What is said about the next Ice Age?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. It could be postponed.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. It could come early.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. It is already late.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. It can’t be predicted.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="4">
	<Text><![CDATA[Should Supermarket Carrier Bags be Banned?               ………………………………New European rules are being brought in to reduce the number of plastic carrier bags we use. In 2011, Italy became the first country in Europe to ban the bags but in 2010 the number of bags in the U.K. went up after four years of going down. More than six billion bags were used and campaigners want to reduce this number. Discarded bags in the sea cause some parts of the ocean to be like ‘plastic soup’, say politicians. Some countries have banned thin plastic bags, including China and South Africa.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[What is said about plastic carrier bags?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. Their use is declining in England]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. Their use is widespread in China]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. They are no longer used in Italy]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. They can be dissolved by the sea]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="5">
	<Text><![CDATA[Europe’s Space Freighter Lifts Off.                        ………………………………The biggest space vehicle servicing the International Space Station (ISS) has taken off from French Guiana. The ATV 3 space truck is taking new supplies of food, water, air, and fuel to the station. It is also carrying experiments and spares for the high-flying astronaut outpost. The ATV is unmanned and is the biggest space vehicle servicing the station. Europe plans to send two further freighters to the station, in 2013 and 2014.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[What is said about ATV 3?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. It is carrying provisions]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. It will be sent to the ISS in 2014]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. It is carrying a passenger]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. A larger vehicle will replace it in 2013]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="6">
	<Text><![CDATA[Seven Rescued After Cargo Ship Crashes in Wales.  ……………………………… A Royal Navy sea king helicopter and two lifeboats rescued seven crew members after a cargo ship ran aground in Wales. The ship crashed into rocks during a storm which saw gale force winds and five-meter tall waves battering it. Assistant Chief Constable Gareth Pritchard said: “This was a very difficult operation involving many agencies in very bad weather. Everyone is delighted that the seven crewmen were rescued without injury and they are safe and well. The Welsh Government is closely monitoring the ship to make sure that fuel doesn’t leak into the sea.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[Which statement is true?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a.  The rescue operation failed]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. Bad weather affected the ship]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. Fuel has spilt from the ship]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. One agency attempted the rescue]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="7">
	<Text><![CDATA[Thieves are Stealing Chewing Gum to Use as Money.  ………………………………A police officer has revealed that thieves are targeting U.K. supermarkets and stealing chewing gum to use as money. An officer from West Mercia Police is investigating the crimes, which have spread across the U.K. Hundreds of pounds worth of chewing gum has been stolen so far. The investigation has revealed that in Romania, chewing gum and small sweets are often given as change instead of low-value coins.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[What is said about the chewing gum?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. There is a shortage of it in Romania]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. It is being used as coins in the U.K]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. It is being stolen from Romanian supermarkets]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. It is being used as currency in Romania]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="8">
	<Text><![CDATA[Scientists Have Created Toxic Glow Fish.                                ………………………………Fish that glow green when put in polluted water have been created in a British lab. It is hoped the luminous zebra fish will help improve the cleanliness of our rivers and help identify dangerous chemicals that get in to our water supply. The fish are designed so that the parts of their bodies harmed by pollutants light up. The advance was made at Exeter University. Chemicals from paints and many plastics often find their way in to our rivers, causing many creatures to have problems breeding as well as causing harm to humans. Professor Charles Tyler, who led the study, said: “This zebrafish gives us a better view than ever before of the potential effects of these chemicals on the body. It is very exciting.”]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[What is said about the toxic glow fish?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. They are not affected by pollutants in the water]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. They will indicate the presence of chemicals]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. They glow green when the water is safe]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. They usually have problems breeding]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="9">
	<Text><![CDATA[261 Schools Get Building Money From Government.  ………………………………A total of 261 schools in England have been told they’re getting money to repair or rebuild their old buildings. The government has announced which schools are being given part of a 2 billion pound pot of cash. But 326 schools missed out on the Priority School Building Program. The previous government had promised to rebuild every secondary school in England. But the new government cancelled the plan, saying it was too expensive.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[What is said about the funds for the schools?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. The previous government cancelled them]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. They will be used to renovate buildings]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. All schools will receive funding]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. The new government initiated the funding]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="10">
	<Text><![CDATA[‘Yes Scotland’ Independence Campaign Kicks Off.  ………………………………The offical campaign to persuade people in Scotland to vote for independence is kicking off. A big vote, expected in 2014, will ask Scots whether they want Scotland to separate from the U.K. and become its own country. The ‘Yes Scotland’ campaign is being led by the Scottish National Party and the launch is set to include Scots from many different backgrounds. An opposing campaign to keep Scotland a part of the UK will also begin soon. Scotland has its own parliament at the moment and it has power over many things such as education, police and transport. But some things such as national security and foreign policy are decided by UK politicians in Westminster. Scotland has been united with England since 1707.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[Which statement is true?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. The campaign has little support]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. Scottish education is controlled by the UK]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. Some Scots want to remain part of the UK]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. The Scottish National Party opposes the campaign]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="11">
	<Text><![CDATA[Giant Pillow Fight Held in Shanghai.  ………………………………A mass pillow fight for 1,000 people has been held in Shanghai. The giant pillow party was held to help people calm down and get rid of their stress. Everyone was given a pillow on arrival on which they wrote the name of the thing or person causing them stress. After a starting whistle, partygoers were free to hit anyone in the room with their pillow. It is the fifth giant pillow fight to be held in Shanghai and has been so popular thinking of similar events in other cities.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[What is said about the pillow fight in Shanghai?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. It caused a lot of stress.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. It is forbidden in other cities.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. It was a huge success.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. It was the first of its kind.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="12">
	<Text><![CDATA[………………………………Six rowers who were crossing the Atlantic Ocean have been rescued after their boat tipped over. The men, five from Britain and one from Ireland, were trying to break a record by rowing from Morocco to Barbados in under 30 days. The crew was 27 days into their adventure when they got into trouble. They were picked up by a ship and are expected to reach land by February 9.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[What could be said about the rowers?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. They were all English.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. They broke a record.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. Their boat turned over.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. They had problems for 27 days.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="13">
	<Text><![CDATA[Government Scraps Homework Rules for English Schools.  ………………………………Official homework guidelines set by the government for English schools have been scrapped. Teachers can decide how much homework to set or whether to set any at all. It’s after some parents complained that too much homework meant kids didn’t have enough time to play, do sports or be with their family. Before, five to seven year old children were expected to do an hour a week, gradually increasing to 2.5 hours each night for pupils aged between fourteen and sixteen.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[What is said about homework?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. Parents want their children to do more]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. The government sets homework rules]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. Teenagers now have to do two hours a night]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. Teachers are responsible for setting homework]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="14">
	<Text><![CDATA[Great Barrier Reef Examined Over Fears of Mining Damage.  ………………………………A United Nations team are in Australia to investigate possible damage to the Great Barrier Reef by mining. Home to 400 types of coral and 1,500 species of fish, the Reef lies off the coast of Queensland, Australia’s biggest coal producer. Environmentalists are worried that coal mining and gas exploration are threatening the reef’s future. They say the plans to increase coal production will mean more big ships carrying coal will damage the reef. John Hepburn from Greenpeace called it, “a reckless expansion that will have direct impact.” The UN team will spend a week examining the reef for any signs of pollution or damage.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[What is said about Great Barrier Reef?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. It is obstructing gas exploration]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. There is apprehension it will suffer damage]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. Coal mining is prohibited in its vicinity]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. The UN found it to be extensively damaged]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="15">
	<Text><![CDATA[Orangutans Show Amazing Skills Building Nests.  ………………………………Scientists have discovered orangutans use really complicated building skills when they build their nests. Research has revealed that the great apes use many different types of branches in lots of different ways to build their homes high up in tree tops. That has amazed scientists from the University of Manchester, who spent a year in South East Asia studying orangutans. But when some can weigh up to 80 bags of sugar, the nests need to be strong! The research took place in Northern Sumatra, an island in Indonesia, where researchers filmed the apes building their nests and took them apart when they were finished with them. The experts learnt that the nests were made up of a really complicated scaffold of branches and twigs and tools were used to help make them. Thick green, flexible branches were used on the outside and thinner leafy twigs on the inside. They can also build a nest in 5 or 6 minutes.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[What is said about Orangutans and their nests?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. Orangutans often dismantle their nests]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. The nests collapse after little use]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. Orangutans spend a lot of time in their nests]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. The nests are built with a variety of foliage]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="16">
	<Text><![CDATA[Pakistan’s Sports Minister Wants to Share His Stamp Collection with World.  ………………………………Pakistan’s sports minister, Mohammed Ali Shah wants to change people’s perception of Pakistan-by turning it into the stamp collecting capital of the world! He said that he wants to promote a softer image of his violence-wracked country through his stamp collection. Mr. Shah has collected more than 10,000 stamps from all over the world, including a very rare ‘Penny Black’, the first sticky-backed postage stamp issued by Britain in 1840. “It is said that philately (stamp collecting) is the king of all hobbies and the hobby of kings,” said Mr. Shah.  Queen Elizabeth of England, too, is known to be a big collector of stamps. But due to email and the decrease in sending mail by post, one post office is closed down in England every month.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[What is said about Pakistan?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. Stamp collecting is very popular in Pakistan]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. Mr. Shah hopes to alter peoples’ views of Pakistan]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. Most of stamps collected in Pakistan come from Britain]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. Many post offices are now closing in Pakistan]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="17">
	<Text><![CDATA[Teachers in Scotland Warned about Using Twitter and Facebook.  ………………………………Teachers in Scotland are being warned about using Twitter and Facebook by the Scottish Secondary Teachers Association. They believe too much information can be revealed on the networking sites, which could lead to teachers becoming too familiar with pupils. New guidelines for teachers on social networking are being drawn up.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[What is said about teachers in Scotland?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. They make excessive use of Twitter and Facebook.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. They use Facebook and Twitter inappropriately.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. Too much information about them has appeared on social networks.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. They have been advised to be cautious with social networks.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="18">
	<Text><![CDATA[Michael Jackson Honored in Hollywood.  ………………………………Michael Jackson has become the first celebrity to have his hand and footprints put on the Hollywood Walk of Fame after his death. Thousands of fans watched his children, Paris, Prince Michael and Blanket, use his famous sequined glove and shoes to make the impressions. Loads of celebrities including Justin Bieber were also at the ceremony. The imprints will be placed alongside other Hollywood screen legends for fans to see.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[Which of the following is true?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. Michael Jackson’s children watched a ceremony in his honor.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. Other celebrities were honored in the same ceremony.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. Michael Jackson’s accessories were used in the ceremony.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. Michael Jackson’s fans can make imprints close to his.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="19">
	<Text><![CDATA[How Much Aid Should The U.K. Give to Other Countries.  ………………………………There is a debate going on about how much aid the U.K. should give to poorer countries. At the moment the U.K. gives around 8 billion pounds a year to other governments. But the government has agreed to meet the United Nation’s target of increasing that amount to nearly 11 billion pounds by the year 2014. They want to make it law that all future governments must stick to the target of 0.7% of the whole country’s income. But the House of Lords say this shouldn’t happen, and that too much aid is going to the wrong places and is ending up with corrupt governments. The government says that cutting the funding could cost thousands of lives.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[What is said about aid?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. The House of Lords believe that the U.K. should give more]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. The government plans to reduce the amount given]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. It is believed that cutting funds could save lives]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. The United Nation’s target is more that what is now given]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="20">
	<Text><![CDATA[Wildlife Film-Maker John Varty Mauled by Tiger.          ………………………………A wildlife documentary-maker is seriously injured after being mauled by a tiger in South Africa. John Varty, 61, who is pioneering a controversial project to create a free-ranging, self-sustaining tiger population outside Asia, was attacked on his Tiger Canyons farm and taken to hospital, where he underwent six-hour emergency surgery. Varty suffered multiple injuries and puncture wounds all over his body and required a blood transfusion. Amanda Appelgryn, spokeswoman for the hospital, said Varty was conscious and she had spoken to him but he is not yet out of danger. She said: “He has multiple injuries all over his whole body but not his face. He’s not stable and he’s not critical, but somewhere in between. It’s best to say he’s in a serious condition. I can’t say he’s out of danger: with wild animals, there’s always the possibility of infection.”]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[What is said about John Varty and the tiger attack?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. His face was badly damaged]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. He is making a good recovery]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. He is unable to communicate]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. His condition could go either way]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="21">
	<Text><![CDATA[Coke and Pepsi Alter Recipe to Avoid Cancer Warning Label.  ………………………………Coca-cola and Pepsi are changing the recipes for their drinks to avoid putting a cancer warning label on the bottle, to comply with California laws. The new recipe for caramel coloring in the drinks has less 4-methylimidazole- a chemical which California has added to its list of carcinogens. But the companies say rolling out the new recipe across the U.S. market makes the drinks more efficient to manufacture. “While we believe that there is no public health risk that justifies any such change, we did ask our caramel suppliers to take this step so that our products would not be subject to the requirement of a scientifically unfounded warning,” a Coca-cola representative told the AP news agency. The chemical has been linked to cancer in mice and rats but there is no evidence that it poses a health risk to humans, said the American Beverage Association, which represents the wider industry.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[Which statement is true?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. The caramel coloring doesn’t contain carcinogens]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. It has not been proved that the coloring is carcinogenic]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. Coca-cola and Pepsi have refused to use cancer-warning labels]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. Coca-cola and Pepsi are now more costly to make]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="22">
	<Text><![CDATA[Is English or Mandarin the Language of the Future?  ………………………………He is unable to communicate]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[Which statement is true?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. Classes are given in English in Malaysian schools]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. Malaysian graduates are sought after in the I.T. industry]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. The standard of English has declined in Malaysia]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. Students from Singapore attend classes in Malaysia]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="23">
	<Text><![CDATA[Dutch Judge Rejects Pleas for Killer Whale Freedom.  ………………………………A Dutch judge has ruled that a rescued female killer whale can be sent to a Canary Islands amusement park, despite pleas to release the animal into the wild. The case of Morgan the orca sharply divided opinion in the Netherlands. The orca was rescued by a dolphinarium in Harderwijk after being found exhausted and starving in shallow waters in the Waddenzee in June 2010. Conservationists are devastated by Monday’s ruling, fearing the move to the Canaries will kill Morgan. The judge in Amsterdam decided however that the orca would have no reasonable chance of survival in the wild. The plan is to transfer Morgan within days to Loro Parque on Tenerife, where she will join five other orcas in a big tank, on show to the public. Ahead of the judge’s ruling the campaign website of the Free Morgan Foundation had been getting more than 50,000 hits a day. Niels van Elk, a vet, thinks Morgan will be better off in captivity than in the wild.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[What is said about Morgan, the killer whale?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. The vet is in agreement with the judge’s decision about where to put her.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. The conservationists are concerned about her ability to survive in the wild.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. She will be kept in isolation after being transported to Tenerife.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d.  The campaign website continues to get more than half a million hits a day.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="24">
	<Text><![CDATA[Pierre Cardin Feud Tears Village Apart.   ………………………………Fashion designer Pierre Cardin has upset the locals in the French village of Lacoste, by buying the AMarquis de Sade’s famous castle and 22 more properties.  Lacoste was once the home of the champion debauchee, the Marquis de Sade .Steep cobbled streets and ancient houses lend an archetypal beauty. This part of the Luberon has always drawn eminent outsiders. But it is the fashion designer, Pierre Cardin, who has left by far the deepest imprint on Lacoste. Indeed for many locals, the Cardin mark is too deep. They wish he would go away. Some say he has destroyed the community by spraying his money and driving up prices. For others, he is a generous philanthropist who provides much-needed local employment. Cardin’s own story is a long march from humble beginnings to fame and enormous wealth. But he has always been regarded as something of an upstart by the fashion elite – no doubt because of his working-class origins.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[Which of the following is true?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. Pierre Cardin is viewed by some as a benefactor.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. Pierre Cardin is highly respected by the fashion elite.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. The Lacoste locals are starting to leave their village.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d.  Prices in Lacoste have decreased with the arrival of Cardin.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="25">
	<Text><![CDATA[Searching for the Origins of Life and our Future.  .………………………………Hollywood is wrong about aliens. They don’t have oddly shaped heads and bulging eyes. Dimitar Sasselov is convinced of that. Professor Sasselov, an astrophysicist, thinks that if life exists elsewhere-and he believes it does- it will likely be based on different building blocks than ours, and so may not even be recognizable as life. A project he’s heading at Harvard University is trying to imagine what life would be like if it were based on different chemicals, conditions and history than we have on Earth. There’s no reason life can only form under our set of circumstances, he says. People have been asking questions like ‘Are we alone?’ since the time of Epicurus. And Sasselov says we probably won’t have a definitive answer in the next century either. Just as Copernicus revolutionized how people viewed themselves and their world 450 years ago, and Darwin did again 150 years ago, so Sasselov says we’re getting close to another transformative moment. This is a fertile time to be looking for life on other planets.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[The astrophysicist, Dimitar Sasselov, believes that;]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. Life could materialize under different conditions.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. We could know within 100 years if there is life on other planets.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. Life on other planets would require conditions similar to Earth.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. This is not an ideal era to be exploring other planets’ life forms.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="26">
	<Text><![CDATA[Seal Pups on the Mend After Being Battered by Storms.  .………………………………The big storms a few weeks ago caused loads of problems across the country – trees were blown down, power lines were cut and roofs were torn off houses. But it wasn’t just humans that had a hard time: seal pups were caught up in the bad weather too. The RSPCA has said it’s seen a big increase in sick seals recently. The storms made it really hard for some of the grey seals to find their way to food and the choppy water meant lots of them were stranded on rocks.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[What is said about the seal pups?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. They caused a lot of problems.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. They were stranded in rough water.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. They had difficulty obtaining food.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. They were unaffected by the storm.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="27">
	<Text><![CDATA[From War to Peace: Sierra Leone Eyes Bird-Watching Money.    ………………………………Sierra Leone is trying to change its image as a war-torn country by promoting ecotourism. If you are planning a bird-watching holiday, Sierra Leone might not be the first destination that jumps to mind. But that could change soon, if the government of this small West African nation gets its way. Earlier this month, Sierra Leone opened the Gola Rainforest National Park, a 71,000-hectare protected area that is home to more bird species than can be found breeding in all of the UK. The government hopes that the new park might help nature-loving tourists see beyond the battered image that defines the country overseas. The reason for that image is a brutal 11-year civil war which claimed the lives of tens of thousands of people. But Sierra Leone has been at peace since the conflict ended in 2002. The park is a region that the environmental group Conservation International has identified as one of the world’s critical biodiversity hotspots.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[The report states that;]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. Sierra Leone is a popular bird-watching destination.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. Sierra Leone remains in the grip of a civil war.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. Gola  National Park houses almost as many bird species as the U.K.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. Gola National Park is of great import as a natural habitat.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="28">
	<Text><![CDATA[Eroding Taboos See Lemurs End Up on Dinner Tables.  ………………………………The erosion of traditional cultural taboos in Madagascar has led to an unsustainable number of lemurs being killed for bush meat. Locals revered these primates, believing that the animals were family ancestors, but the influx of outside influences has seen a breakdown in these views. Some species do not reach maturity for up to nine years and produce offspring once every two or three years. A survey of locals’ eating habits showed that hunting of protected species in eastern Madagascar was increasing. It suggested the rise in illegal hunting was the result of rapid social change, an increase in demand for meat and a decline in traditional taboos. “When you have globalization and outside influences, traditional cultures break down and change faster,” explained co-author Julia Jones from Bangor University. “What seems to be happening in some of the remote areas around the nation’s eastern rainforests is that a lot of legal gold mining is springing up, so peoplBe from outside are moving into the area.”]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[What is said about Lemurs in Madagascar?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. They are traditionally killed for bush meat.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. They usually produce offspring every year.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. They are being affected by the illegal gold mining industry.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. They were held in high regard by local people.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="29">
	<Text><![CDATA[Different Countries Have Different Emotions.  ………………………………It has been assumed since Charles Darwin’s time that six basic emotions are shown on everyone’s face in the same way: happiness, sadness, surprise, fear, disgust and anger. This is known as the universality hypothesis. Scientists tested this out recently by using a computer simulation of a face, which could show every possible combination of facial muscle movement. Then they asked 15 white Europeans/Americans and 15 East Asians to put thousands of its expressions into categories. Although the Westerners in the study separated all the expressions into the expected six emotional categories, the Asians showed there was an overlap of emotions. The scientists think that this could be because the theory ignores emotions such as shame, pride and guilt. Westerners also use different groups of muscles to express the six emotions while, with Asian people, a lot of the emotion comes from the eyes. The experts say that over time, different cultures have changed the way they communicate with their facial expressions.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[Which statement is true?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. Westerners express emotion mainly through the eyes]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. The Asians in the study separated the emotions]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. The result from the Westerners studied was as predicted]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. Most cultures have retained their facial communication method]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="30">
	<Text><![CDATA[Cheryl Cole Feared For Her Life on a Plane in Germany. CBBC  ………………………………Cheryl Cole says she feared for her life when she got trapped on her private jet during a lightning storm. The singer was at Frankfurt airport in Germany during a tour when lightning struck the runway. Her plane wasn’t allowed to take off and no-one was allowed to leave the aircraft as it was too dangerous. Cheryl was so scared but she thought: “This is it. I’ve got an album to promote and I’ve got so much yet to do.”But she said that thinking about her charity mountain climb in 2009 helped her focus. “I remembered I’d climbed Kilimanjaro, so I took a bit of strength from that.”]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[What is said about the singer, Cheryl Cole?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. She was in a storm on Kilimanjaro]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. Her plane was grounded during a storm]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. She refused to fly during a storm]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. Her plane flew through a storm]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
</exam>
