<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?><exam id_exam="8" title="Departamento de Idiomas. Escuela de Guerra | INGLÉS" fecha="EXAMEN DE NOV 12" tipo="Normal">
<intro1><![CDATA[En las sucesivas presentaciones usted encontrará preguntas de relacionadas con el texto redactado.]]></intro1>
<intro2><![CDATA[Después de leer y comprender el texto presentado deberá responder a una de las preguntas de la parte inferior.]]></intro2>
<intro3><![CDATA[Gracias por su colaboración. A continuación podrá <strong>imprimir</strong> las respuestas que han sido seleccionadas, o bien imprimirlas en un archivo <strong>pdf</strong> para su entrega al profesor correspondiente.]]></intro3>
<tiempoGlobal><![CDATA[75]]></tiempoGlobal>
<timeOver><![CDATA[Su tiempo ha terminado. Pulse finalizar e imprima sus respuestas]]></timeOver>
<user id= "1">LABRADO GOMEZ, CARLOS TIM: 51358887#</user>

<user id= "2">LAGUNA PEREZ, JAVIER TIM: 51652408#</user>

<user id= "3">CAP TOVAR HERNÁNDEZ, GERARDO TIM: 09279594#</user>

<user id= "4">MERINO TORO, LA BEGO TIM: 52104944#</user>

<user id= "5">TCOL. D. ANTONIO PIÑA SANCHEZ TIM: 43012165#</user>

<user id= "6">TCOL. D. ANGEL FERNANDEZ TUR TIM: 45068182#</user>

<user id= "7">T TE. D. ANDRES TORRES CASO TIM: 28800128#</user>

<user id= "8">CAP. ART.  JOSE  FRANCISCO   CAMPOS  BARBERO TIM: 06965997#</user>

<user id= "9">CAP. CAB.  GABRIEL     ECHEVERRIA  URQUIZU TIM: 15992562#</user>

<user id= "10">CAP. ABSTO.  MANUEL  JOSE    CEREZO       LOPEZ TIM: 30499977#</user>

<user id= "11">JAVIER CANDAU ROMERO TIM: 28696353#</user>

<user id= "12">TCOL. ANGEL MURILLO GÓMEZ TIM: 50701438#</user>

<user id= "13">CTE. D. JOSÉ ALFONSO ROMÁN BIENES TIM: 11735404#</user>

<user id= "14">TCOL. D. FRANCISCO JOSÉ LUGO PÉREZ TIM: 03824117#</user>

<user id= "15">TCOL. D. BALTASAR BONILLA MORALES TIM: 78074909#</user>

<user id= "16">TCOL. D. PABLO FERNANDO LESTAU MORELL TIM: 31648311#</user>

<user id= "17">CTE. D. MANUEL CARRASCO GÓMEZ TIM: 50843117#</user>

<user id= "18">CTE. D. AGUSTÍN FÉLIX AHEDO PELLITERO TIM: 21500338#</user>

<user id= "19">CAP. D. ANTONIO Mª CLARET IBÁÑEZ TARRADELLAS TIM: 33934211#</user>

<user id= "20">CTE. D. FRANCISCO GÓMEZ PAREDES TIM: 32678655#</user>

<user id= "21">CTE. D. BONIFACIO DE LA VIUDA LOZANO TIM: 09259803#</user>

<user id= "22">CAP. D. JUAN JERÓNIMO VILLALÓN CARBELLIDO TIM: 75757745#</user>

<user id= "23">CAP. D. ÁNGEL LUIS PIÑEIRO BUSTABAD TIM: 32633576#</user>

<user id= "24">CAP. D. PEDRO GARCÍA AGUADO TIM: 00379813#</user>

<user id= "25">CTE. D. DANIEL DONOSO RODRÍGUEZ TIM: 07525490#</user>

<user id= "26">CAP. D. MIGUEL A. ESTEVE AGUILAR TIM: 73770475#</user>

<user id= "27">TTE. D. JOSÉ OCTAVIO BOIRA MORENO TIM: 52887029#</user>

<user id= "28">TTE. D. CARLOS CLARAMONTE MARZO TIM: 72985673#</user>

<user id= "29">TTE. D. ALBERTO RUÍZ BIELSA TIM: 03913140#</user>

<user id= "30">TTE. D. ENRIQUE SÁNCHEZ DÍAZ TIM: 44352647#</user>

<user id= "31">TTE. D. JOAQUÍN PELLEGRÍN GAYÁN TIM: 72998617#</user>

<user id= "32">TCOL. D. SANTIAGO ÁLVAREZ HERRERO TIM: 09758017#</user>

<user id= "33">CAP. D. LEOPOLDO SANTOS SANTOS TIM: 07512351#</user>

<user id= "34">CAP. D. LUIS MARTÍNEZ THOMAS TIM: 09419326#</user>

<user id= "35">TCOL. D. RODOLFO MARTÍNEZ AZOFRA TIM: 32033891#</user>

<user id= "36">CTE. D. DARÍO DE JULIÁN FRÍAS TIM: 29119215#</user>

<user id= "37">CTE. D. JAVIER VÁZQUEZ HERMOSO TIM: 03457112#</user>

<user id= "38">TCOL. D. ALBERTO JAVIER GARCÍA ROMERA TIM: 24225777#</user>

<user id= "39">TCOL. D. PABLO MORA BURBANO TIM: 50828592#</user>

<user id= "40">CTE. D. MIGUEL DUEÑAS GONZÁLEZ TIM: 11821590#</user>

<user id= "41">TCOL. D. BENJAMÍN RIVED LEDESMA TIM: 25140809#</user>

<user id= "42">TCOL. D. CARLOS GALLEGO REMIRO TIM: 25442191#</user>

<user id= "43">CTE. D. ÁNGEL TOMÉ CARRILLO TIM: 45279892#</user>

<user id= "44">CTE. D. JOSÉ MANUEL FERNÁNDEZ MELÓN TIM: 09337260#</user>

<user id= "45">TCOL. D. JULIO JAVIER CARDERO ESCOS TIM: 13113534#</user>

<user id= "46">TTE. D. FERNANDO VIDALES BERROYA TIM: 51460093#</user>

<user id= "47">CTE. D. RODRIGO JOSÉ HERNÁNDEZ NAVARRO TIM: 29113542#</user>

<user id= "48">CAP. D. PEDRO ANTONIO MARTÍNEZ IRANZO TIM: 11846830#</user>

<user id= "49">CAP. D. CONSUELO DELAGE GARCÍA DE ÁNGULO TIM: 47768761#</user>

<user id= "50">TTE. D. VÍCTOR MONREAL GUMIEL TIM: 29133751#</user>

<user id= "51">COR. D. JOSÉ MANUEL SIABA PORTELA TIM: 33246623#</user>

<user id= "52">TCOL. D. JOSÉ ANTONIO ARAUZO MARTÍNEZ TIM: 13117909#</user>

<user id= "53">TCOL. D. MARCOS ÁNGEL SANZ OBERBERGER TIM: 25143730#</user>

<user id= "54">CTE. D. JUAN CARLOS MILLÓN PINTOS TIM: 35324071#</user>

<user id= "55">CAP. D. ÁLVARO LOMAS CARDONA TIM: 25079402#</user>

<user id= "56">TTE. D. ESTEBAN VICENTE BOISSEAU TIM: 29170771#</user>

<user id= "57">TTE. D. FRANCISCO JOSÉ OSUNA LOZANO TIM: 41507482#</user>

<user id= "58">TTE. D. SERGIO VILLAESCUSA GONZÁLEZ TIM: 78918065#</user>

<user id= "59">TTE. D. JOSÉ ANTONIO PEREA ÁLVAREZ TIM: 75890640#</user>

<user id= "60">TTE. D. MARIO LOZANO BENITO TIM: 20262808#</user>

<user id= "61">BG. D. ANTONIO DURAN CARRILLO DURAN CARRILLO TIM: 02872622#</user>

<user id= "62">BG. D. MOISES BARRANCO SERRANOS BARRANCO SERRANOS TIM: 25456698#</user>

<user id= "63">BG. D. MANUEL MARIA GARCIA VICENTE GARCIA VICENTE TIM: 30577814#</user>

<user id= "64">BG. D. JOSE JAVIER  ALOS VELERT  ALOS VELERT TIM: 22553148#</user>

<user id= "65">BG. D. JOSE LUIS  SALGADO DE DIEGO  SALGADO DE DIEGO TIM: 05264084#</user>

<user id= "66">BG. D. GABRIEL MARTINEZ SECALL MARTINEZ SECALL TIM: 38113350#</user>

<user id= "67">BG. D. JOSE LUIS DE LAS PEÑAS PLANA DE LAS PEÑAS PLANA TIM: 00413049#</user>

<user id= "68">SBTE. D. JACINTO JOSE CALABOR ALONSO CALABOR ALONSO TIM: 22539187#</user>

<user id= "69">SGTO 1º. D. JUAN IGNACIO HERNANDEZ LEAL HERNANDEZ LEAL TIM: 29115714#</user>

<user id= "70">BG. D. ANTONIO PEREZ GOMEZ PEREZ GOMEZ TIM: 27297055#</user>

<user id= "71">SGTO 1º. D. JAVIER IRANZO GARCIA IRANZO GARCIA TIM: 25423055#</user>

<user id= "72">SGTO 1º. D. FELIX ORTEGA PRIETO ORTEGA PRIETO TIM: 04595120#</user>

<user id= "73">SGTO 1º. D. FRANCISCO POLO GONZÁLEZ POLO GONZÁLEZ TIM: 30817212#</user>

<user id= "74">SGTO 1º. D. MANUEL  BARBOSA ROVIGO BARBOSA ROVIGO TIM: 10900268#</user>

<user id= "75">BG. D. JOAQUIN GONZALEZ LOPEZ GONZALEZ LOPEZ TIM: 50708673#</user>

<user id= "76">BG. D. FRANCISCO JESUS PEÑA DIAZ PEÑA DIAZ TIM: 33502596#</user>

<user id= "77">BG. D. CARLOS TIMOTEO VEGA MARTIN VEGA MARTIN TIM: 11935408#</user>

<user id= "78">BG. D. LUIS ALBERTO GUERRA SANZO GUERRA SANZO TIM: 09797900#</user>

<user id= "79">BG. D. LUIS  CAMPILLO BAREZ CAMPILLO BAREZ TIM: 45075011#</user>

<user id= "80">SGTO. D. JOSE ANTONIO CACERES BAENA CACERES BAENA TIM: 50988746#</user>

<user id= "81">CTE. JUARROS LAFUENTE, BERNARDINO TIM: 13304139#</user>

<user id= "82">CTE. GOMEZ RAMOS, ANTONIO VICTORIANO TIM: 50092021#</user>

<user id= "83">CTE. PEREZ DE LUCAS, CESAR TIM: 03469246#</user>

<user id= "84">SGT1º. GATON MIGUELSANZ, RAUL TIM: 12379098#</user>

<user id= "85">TCOL. CORPAS RUIZ, ANTONIO TIM: 30498869#</user>

<user id= "86">CTE. GARCES MENDUIÑA, JOSE MIGUEL TIM: 30806026#</user>

<user id= "87">TCOL. GUASCH AGUILAR, MARIANO TIM: 22546098#</user>

<user id= "88">CTE. HERRANZ SANZ, JAVIER TIM: 51075280#</user>

<user id= "89">TCOL. MORENO SANTOS, MANUEL TIM: 31234018#</user>

<user id= "90">CTE. SAN SEGUNDO CAMPO, MIGUEL ANGEL TIM: 06568918#</user>

<user id= "91">CTE. VALCAZAR ALONSO, CESAR TIM: 12758488#</user>

<user id= "92">CTE. MARTIN HERRERA, RAUL TIM: 50701152#</user>

<user id= "93">CTE. MUÑIZ BASCUAS, JOSE DANIEL TIM: 52683894#</user>

<user id= "94">CTE. NIEVAS GUTIERREZ, JOSE MIGUEL TIM: 24167228#</user>

<user id= "95">CTE. SANTE ABAL, MANUEL TIM: 52493903#</user>

<user id= "96">TCOL. DE LUCAS LOBO, RAFAEL TIM: 50416386#</user>

<user id= "97">CTE. GARCIA SERON, PEDRO JOSE TIM: 22988923#</user>

<user id= "98">CTE. MARQUEZ DE LA CALLEJA, FERNANDO TIM: 02902556#</user>

<user id= "99">SGT1º. MORENO HERRANZ, DANIEL TIM: 50189566#</user>

<user id= "100">CTE. RIVAS CASTEL, DANIEL TIM: 51684560#</user>

<user id= "101">STTE. D. JUAN FERNANDO SILVA MARTINEZ TIM: 08797742#</user>

<user id= "102">STTE. D. RAMON JIMENEZ HUESO TIM: 27264940#</user>

<user id= "103">STTE. D. ANDRES CARDEÑOSA RIVERO TIM: 01107556#</user>

<user id= "104">STTE. D. JUAN LUIS BERENGUER DE DIEGO TIM: 00804792#</user>

<user id= "105">STTE. D. JUAN JOSE INES DE DIEGO TIM: 14594214#</user>

<user id= "106">STTE. D. JOSE CAROLLO RAÑA TIM: 30552550#</user>

<user id= "107">STTE. D. ANGEL GALVEZ URREA TIM: 05170310#</user>

<user id= "108">BG. D. FRANCISCO JAVIER MARTINEZ GONZALEZ TIM: 50042602#</user>

<user id= "109">BG. D. SANTIAGO A. SERRANO DIAZ TIM: 25073773#</user>

<user id= "110">BG. D. JUAN VALLEJO RUIZ TIM: 52542807#</user>

<user id= "111">BG. D. PEDRO JOSE MANCHEÑO CARPINTERO TIM: 05385260#</user>

<user id= "112">BG. D. JESUS ANGEL MUÑOZ ZAPATA TIM: 50164553#</user>

<user id= "113">BG. D. JAIME SANCHEZ ALONSO TIM: 11772183#</user>

<user id= "114">BG. D. JOSE ANTONIO CHAVES ARIZA TIM: 25069497#</user>

<user id= "115">BG. D. AURELIO SALVADOR LUJAN TIM: 04578156#</user>

<user id= "116">BG. D. LUIS ANTONIO GOMEZ LOPEZ TIM: 32767933#</user>

<user id= "117">BG. D. FRANCISCO JAVIER AVELLANEDA GARCIA TIM: 45274051#</user>

<user id= "118">BG. D. MANUEL RUIZ FERNANDEZ TIM: 07521230#</user>

<user id= "119">SGTO 1º. D. SANTIAGO CRESPO GUTIERREZ TIM: 31254450#</user>

<user id= "120">SGTO 1º. D. ANTONIO CUADRADO TOLEDO TIM: 45283372#</user>

<user id= "121">SGTO 1º. D. ALONSO ANTONIO MORENO ALMAGRO TIM: 52816995#</user>

<user id= "122">SGTO 1º. D. FRANCISCO DIAZ ARRIERO TIM: 04194064#</user>

<user id= "123">SGTO 1º. D. VALENTIN RODOLFO SANTAMARIA GALEA TIM: 50454111#</user>

<user id= "124">SGTO 1º. D. FRANCISCO MANUEL VILLA MATEO TIM: 52693767#</user>

<user id= "125">SGTO 1º. D. LUIS UCETA GARCIA TIM: 52501920#</user>

<user id= "126">SGTO 1º. D. ENRIQUE SANCHO DEL BARRIO TIM: 13786571#</user>

<user id= "127">SGTO 1º. D. JOSE Mª HERNANDEZ ALDEHUELO TIM: 02898566#</user>

<user id= "128">SGTO 1º. D. JUAN CARLOS GONZALEZ VAZQUEZ TIM: 16300776#</user>

<user id= "129">SGTO 1º. D. JOSE PIGUEIRAS FERNANDEZ TIM: 33996143#</user>

<user id= "130">SGTO 1º. D. JOSE ROMERO TORRENTE TIM: 32662507#</user>

<user id= "131">SGTO 1º. D. FRANCISCO HUERTA ESTRUGA TIM: 03861914#</user>

<user id= "132">SGTO 1º. D. BENJAMIN CANTILLO MORENO TIM: 52468216#</user>

<user id= "133">SGTO 1º. D. RAFAEL BAENA LOPEZ TIM: 31864651#</user>

<user id= "134">SGTO 1º. D. MANUEL BARANGUA AZNAR TIM: 34857955#</user>

<user id= "135">SGTO 1º. D. J IGNACIO SANCHEZ DE VENA TIM: 13153854#</user>

<user id= "136">SGTO 1º. D. JUAN A GUTIERREZ SOBRADO TIM: 28952241#</user>

<user id= "137">SGTO 1º. D. ALBERTO COLOMO LOECHES TIM: 08998551#</user>

<user id= "138">SGTO 1º. D. JOSE PINO CAMACHO TIM: 25587217#</user>

<user id= "139">SGTO 1º. D. EDUARDO JOSE ALVAREZ MONTES TIM: 11427316#</user>

<user id= "140">SGTO 1º. D. SERGIO CALZADO PEREZ TIM: 09804963#</user>

<user id= "141">SGTO 1º. D. JUAN ANTONIO GALLEGO RUIZ TIM: 80063549#</user>

<user id= "142">SGTO 1º. D. MARCO ANTONIO ANTUNEZ DIAZ TIM: 28758203#</user>

<user id= "143">SGTO 1º. D. JOAQUIN MIGUEL MIRANDA MARTINEZ TIM: 34859515#</user>

<user id= "144">SGTO 1º. D. DAVID MARTINEZ HERNANDEZ TIM: 30835741#</user>

<user id= "145">SGTO 1º. D. DAVID VICENTE BARROSO TIM: 12388692#</user>

<user id= "146">SGTO. D. MANUEL SAEZ CORCHERO TIM: 08878219#</user>

<user id= "147">SGTO. D. PEDRO MARTIN DE ARCO TIM: 45300855#</user>

<user id= "148">SGTO. D. CARLOS TERRIZA TORRES TIM: 05699503#</user>

<question nquest="1">
	<Text><![CDATA[Afghan President Hamid Karzai has said international support after foreign forces withdraw in 2014 is crucial if Afghanistan is to remain stable. His comments opened a major global conference on Afghanistan’s future in the German city of Bonn. It comes 10 years after a similar gathering held in the city, weeks after the Taliban fell from power. But key player Pakistan is boycotting this round in protest at a Nato attack on a border checkpoint. NATO apologized for the air strike on 26 November 2011 in which 24 Pakistani troops were killed and US President Barack Obama also offered his condolences, but Pakistan has insisted it will not reverse its decision on the talks. President Karzai hailed the progress Afghanistan has made in the decade since the last conference, but warned that such gains were by no means secure. He said the conference presented an opportunity for Afghanistan to consolidate its gains.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[1.- Which of the following is true?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) The summit on Afghanistan’s future is the first of its kind]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) President Karzai has condemned the lack of progress in Afghanistan]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) The US was in opposition to the summit]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) Pakistan spurned the proceedings]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="2">
	<Text><![CDATA[The Honduran Congress has voted to ban motorcyclists from riding with passengers in a bid to curb a spate of drive-by killings. The move follows two high-profile murders this week, both blamed on gunmen on motorbikes. Honduras has the world’s highest murder rate: 82 per 100,000 people a year. During a session held in private because of security fears, legislators approved a decree limiting the number of people allowed on a motorbike to just one. The measure, which will last for six months, was requested by President Porfirio Lobo, whose government is facing rising crime. Motorcycles have been used in several high-profile murders. Honduras is a key transit country for cocaine smuggled from South America and on to the US market. In November the Honduran authorities began deploying troops to carry out policing duties. The police force itself is undergoing a purge amid efforts to root out officers with links to organized crime.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[2.- Which of the following is true?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) The Honduran Congress is moving to protect privacy]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) Efforts are being made to eliminate corruption in the military]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) The military is now active in tackling crime problems in Honduras]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) Motorbike riding will be banned for six months in Honduras]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="3">
	<Text><![CDATA[Prince Harry had to swap boats during his Jubilee tour when the speed boat he was travelling on broke down. Harry ‘abandoned ship’ and hopped on board a press and media boat following the tour. He was off the Bahamas as part of his official tour of the Caribbean and was supposed to join the crew of a Royal Bahamian Defense Force patrol boat on a naval exercise. He eventually landed on tiny Harbor Island, where he met crowds of tourists and locals.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[3.-When did Prince Harry’s boat break?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) When he was leaving the Bahamas]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) When he arrived on Harbor Island]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) During a naval exercise]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) When he was close to the Bahamas]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="4">
	<Text><![CDATA[A six-year-old girl has survived after being trapped under ice in a river and spending four days in a coma. The girl and her brother were playing on ice when it gave way. Medics say that the girl has not suffered any injuries and that she has been sitting up in bed and enjoying an ice cream.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[4.- What happened to the young girl?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) She was wounded by the ice]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) She was stuck under the ice]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) She was pushed under the ice]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) She was drowned under the ice]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="5">
	<Text><![CDATA[Two daring commando raids by two nations in one day against Somali pirates show that some naval forces are taking a harder line, perhaps because nothing else they have tried has stopped the rise of lawlessness off the east coast of Africa. The raids by South Korea and Malaysia could be a sign of more aggressive tactics to come – both by navies and by pirates responding to them. Experts say pirates could increasingly use hostages as human shields if raids become more common. The European Union Naval Force refuses to raid hijacked ships out of concern for the safety of hostages, but frustration is rising. Despite patrols by an international flotilla of warships, drones patrolling the Indian Ocean and diverse strategies employed, including the sinking of pirate boats, Somali pirates have been relentless.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[5.- The report states that;]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) The raids are reducing acts of piracy]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) The European Union’s naval force participates in raids]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) Hostages are increasingly being used as human shields]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) The raids are carried out as a last resort]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="6">
	<Text><![CDATA[A South African gold mining company owned by members of the Mandela and Zuma families is accused of exploiting its political connections to avoid punishment over its abuse of workers. The company is also accused of profiting from selling mine assets it does not own- a claim it vehemently denies.                                                                                                                                                            Aurora Empowerment Systems, took control of two gold mines just outside of Johannesburg around 18 months ago. Today, South Africa’s mining unions claim the company owes its workers more than 12m rand (1.8m) in unpaid salaries. The managing director of Aurora is Zondwa Gadafi Mandela, grandson of Nelson Mandela. The chairman is the nephew of President Jacob Zuma. Despite having no previous experience in the mining industry, a high court-appointed liquidator gave Aurora control of two gold mines after the previous owner went bust. Since then, the company has been at the centre of huge controversy in South Africa, with critics claiming that the company has committed multiple legal and regulatory infringements, but has escaped any kind of sanction because of the significant political connections of its senior management.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[6.- It is stated in the article that Aurora;]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) Has been exempt from penalties because of its ties]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) Has an extensive background in mining]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) Has been convicted of selling mine assets it doesn’t own]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) Has to pay the workers’ unions a lot of money]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="7">
	<Text><![CDATA[Japan’s government is set to suspend all cattle shipments from Fukushima as concerns over radiation-tainted beef escalate. Senior Vice Health Minister Kohei Otsuka said beef from surrounding areas may also be affected. Increasing numbers of cows have been found to have consumed rice straw containing high levels of radioactive caesium. The straw was harvested from rice paddies in Fukushima prefecture after the devastating earthquake and tsunami knocked out critical cooling systems at the local nuclear plant leading to a meltdown. More than four months on, radioactive material continues to escape from the facility. Distributors across the country have bought meat from exposed cows and some of it could have already reached consumers. The major supermarket chain Aeon said that hundreds of kilos of the beef have been sold at 14 of its stores in Tokyo and the surrounding areas. The retailer said it would start to check beef shipments from all areas for contamination. The government has also acknowledged that the problem could be wider than just Fukushima.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[7.- According to the report;]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) The tainted beef has been sold in Fukushima only]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) Transportation of cattle from Fukushima has been postponed]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) The radioactive material is no longer leaking out of the facilities]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) Distributors are boycotting the purchase of beef]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="8">
	<Text><![CDATA[The man who led a legal battle which led to the recent discovery of treasure worth billions of dollars in an Indian Temple has died at the age of 70. Sundar Rajan, petitioned for the vaults of the sixteenth century temple in Kerala to be opened. Inside, investigators found gold and silver jewelry and precious stones which had been hidden for decades. Local legend had long held that vast riches had been interred in the walls and vaults of the temple. Sundar Rajan went to the Supreme Court asking that the state take over control of the temple, saying the current temple trust was incapable of protecting the wealth inside. The court ordered an inspection of the temple vaults and when inspectors broke through, they found huge amounts of treasure, including diamonds, jewelry pots and gold coins. Neither the state of Kerala nor the descendants of the royal family have made any claim on the treasure, which they say is the property of the temple and its deity. But the discovery has sparked a public debate, with many believing the items should be put in museums or sold and the profits used for the public good.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[8.- According to the report;]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) Sundar Rajan didn’t have confidence in the state.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) There is contention over the fortune.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) Sundar Rajan was opposed to the opening of the vaults.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) The temple was never believed to contain such wealth.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="9">
	<Text><![CDATA[I recently reported on an organization called KaBOOM! which helps residents in low-income communities across the United States build playgrounds and take steps towards re-creating their communities. In the poorest areas of the country, there is a severe shortage of quality play spaces for children; some areas have been described as ‘play deserts’. This problem has drawn the attention of child advocates and some, but not enough, policy makers. Park and recreation budgets are often the first to be slashed when budgets are tightened. In recent years, groups like KaBOOM! have helped to fill the gap by raising private funds to finance playgrounds. But KaBOOM! goes a step further: it shows locals how to organize and build playgrounds themselves. If each generation of citizens has to rediscover its capacity for societal renewal, the past can certainly serve as a guide. Why did community playgrounds and children’s vegetable gardens end?]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[9.- According to the report;]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) KaBOOM! has received the support of policy makers]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) KaBOOM!’s beginning was influenced by budget cuts]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) KaBOOM ! trains locals in fundraising methods]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) KaBOOM! was founded in a previous era]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="10">
	<Text><![CDATA[Six major US tobacco companies have defeated a lawsuit by hospitals seeking compensation for treating patients with smoking-related illnesses. Thirty-seven hospitals in the state of Missouri had claimed cigarette companies delivered an “unreasonably dangerous” product. They sought more than $455m reimbursement for treating uninsured smokers who had not paid for care. The hospitals treat many destitute, non-paying patients. They said medical ethics required them to treat people in need, regardless of their ability to pay. In the case, the hospitals claimed that tobacco companies manipulated the nicotine content in cigarettes and misrepresented the health effects of smoking. But a jury in St. Louis rejected their claim. An official from Lorillard, another company in the case, said: “Compelling evidence was presented to the jury, including testimony from hospital witnesses that confirmed the hospitals were not financially damaged as they asserted.”]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[10.- One of the reasons that the hospitals lost the case appears to be that;]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) The illnesses patients had were found to be unrelated to smoking]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) They had refused to treat certain patients]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) Hospital funds were not found to be badly affected]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) The tobacco companies were found to be losing profits]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="11">
	<Text><![CDATA[It’s three o’clock in the morning and Jaycee Solis is taking a call from a client who wants to book a flight from Detroit to New York. Jaycee’s American accent is so convincing that the US caller is almost certainly unaware that he’s on the other side of the world, in the Philippines. It’s this accent coupled with the high number of fluent English speakers that is making the Philippines the new destination of choice for international companies wanting to outsource their call centers. “In voice-based business, we really excel,” says Bong Borja , the Philippine president of a call center  company. To American ears, Filipinos often sound clearer than agents in India – the king of the call centre industry. Mr. Borja says. “That’s the reason some companies in India are moving to the Philippines.” Some are even run by Indians, and many employ a high number of Indian expatriates on their management staff. People with these management skills “can only be found in India – they have the expertise and they were there a couple of years ahead of us,” says Mr. Borja.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[11.- According to the report;]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) The Philippines has now taken the lead in the call centre business]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) India has been the leader in the call centre business due to its high level of English]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) Philippine success in the call centre business is due to its business skills]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) Companies favor the Philippines over India regarding language aptitude]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[12.- The report states:]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) Many of the call centers are under Indian management]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) American customers find it easier to speak with Indian agents]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) Some Filipino call centers are moving to India]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) More Filipinos are being trained for management positions]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="12">
	<Text><![CDATA[Cuban and American politicians have celebrated together at the opening of Hemingway’s, an invitation –only bar located in a Washington DC embassy. It started like a typical Washington DC function. Men and women in dark suits milled around a formal room in the Swiss Embassy.  But after a series of speeches, guests were led to the back of the room, and into an entirely different experience. They had entered Hemingway’s, a bar celebrating the American writer who made his home in Cuba. There, the floors were covered in terracotta tile, while wooden fans whirred above. Bartenders poured cocktails under a brass replica of Hemingway’s signature. Aside from the fact that it serves liquor, Hemingway’s isn’t a bar in the traditional sense. Tucked inside the embassy, where the Cuban Interests Section resides, the bar has a strict invitation-only list. It will be used for entertaining guest of the Interest Section, so tourists hoping to catch happy hour are out of luck. It’s illegal for the bar to conduct any commerce, but the embassy is free from the trade embargo that forbids importing products from the communist country. So drinks were free, made with Cuban rum that’s normally impossible to find in the U.S.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[13.- Which of the following is true?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) The celebration took place in Havana]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) Drinks were served free of charge]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) Cuban rum was not available]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) Tourists enjoy coming to the bar for ‘Happy Hour’]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[14.- What is said about the bar, ‘Hemingway’s’?]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) It is now open to the public]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) It is very conventional]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) Access to it is restricted]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) It turns over a large profit]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="13">
	<Text><![CDATA[Last December a policeman in a small town near Rome put on a balaclava, kidnapped his neighbor’s teenage son and demanded an 85,000 euro ransom. Quickly tracked down and arrested by his fellow officers, he told them that he was up to his neck in debts as he lost everything at video poker. Bizarre stories like this are popping up more often as Italians develop a serious gambling habit. Italy has now moved into the number one spot for gambling in Europe after overtaking the U.K. The boom has been driven by the legalization of slot machines which have overtaken lotteries, horses and football to account for more than half of today’s total spending. “Until the 1990s it was disapproved of and the government’s tendency was to control it,” said sociologist Maurizio Fiasco. “Then it became a useful revenue.” While the gambling parlors provide a revenue for the cash-strapped government, the mafia has also moved in for its cut – allegedly using front companies to obtain licenses then laundering drug money through operations.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[15.- What is said about gambling in Italy?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) It is making Italians progressively richer]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) U.K. has more gamblers than Italy]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) Slot machines dominate the gambling scene]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) Gambling is still widely disapproved of]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[16.- What is said about the mafia?]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) They have taken over the gambling business]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) They access the gambling business through false enterprises]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) Gambling is their main source of revenue]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) They are rarely able to obtain licenses for businesses]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="14">
	<Text><![CDATA[A National Trust farm is to be run by online subscribers voting on which crops to grow and livestock to rear. For a 30-pound annual fee, 10,000 farm followers will help manage Wimpole Home Farm, in Cambridgeshire. The ‘My Farm’ project aims to reconnect people with where their food comes from. It was partly inspired by the online Face book game Farmville and follows the example of Ebbsfleet Football Club which is run on a similar basis. Wimpole Home Farm, which is converting to organic, is currently commercially self-sustaining. The 1,200 acre site is home to rare breeds of sheep, cattle, poultry, horses and goats and produces meat, eggs, wheat and oil seed rape. Subscribers will be expected to make key decisions on which crops to plant, which animals to buy and whether to put in measures such as new hedgerows to help wildlife. They will be asked to make 12 major monthly decisions during the course of the year as well as other choices. The options put to members will be within parameters dictated by climate, legislation, and the requirements of the environmental stewardship scheme which the farm is signed up to, as well as the heritage protection given to the estate.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[17.- The ‘My Farm’ project was set up partly to;]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) Reacquaint people with food production]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) Inspire people to grow their own food]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) To encourage people to participate in the game Farmville]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) To compete with the ‘My Football Club’ project]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[18.- When making decisions about the farm, subscribers will be obliged to consider;]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) The opinions of experts]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) The method of hedgerows cultivation]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) Climatic conditions]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) The rarity of the livestock breeds]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="15">
	<Text><![CDATA[Arsenic mines and factories in Georgia abandoned after the fall of the Soviet Union are leaking toxic chemicals, and scientific studies show high rates of illness in local children. But it seems villagers in Uravi, high in the Caucasus mountains in north-west Georgia, are being kept in the dark and locals know nothing about the harm the pollution could be doing to their young. The government is aware of the problem, but with its economy still only 60% of what it was in Soviet times, the country just does not have the necessary resources, says environment minister Giorgi Khachidze. “All over the country we have the legacy of pesticides, landmines, abandoned factories, sources of radiation. Every day we get information about something and we just don’t have the money to sort out all these in a day.” Uravi is a beautiful spot, where hills dotted with small wooden houses rise up form the river to peaks covered in snow. But locals call this the Black Valley. Zaza Bochirishvili, who runs a local NGO campaigning on green issues, says the whole area is polluted. “All mountain rivers should have fish in them but this river does not.” Recent tests show arsenic levels in the soil around the village are 20-30 times higher than normal. Other scientific studies have found arsenic in the blood of local children.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[19.- The problem in Uravi has been worsened by;]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) The fall of the Soviet Union]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) The fact that it is short of funds]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) The nature of its landscape]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) The fact that it has a predominantly young population]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[20.- What is said about the local population in Uravi?]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) They are not being well-informed about the problem]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) They are actively resolving the problem]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) They are protesting the government’s inaction]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) They are leaving the area]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="16">
	<Text><![CDATA[When Botswana achieved independence in 1966, it was one of Africa’s poorest countries with few schools or hospitals and only a handful of university graduates. Today the country has a national digital telephone network and universal access to health and education, which are largely funded by the government. Botswana has mineral wealth, mainly in the form of diamonds, as well as political stability. But these alone cannot explain why Botswana has fared so much better than many countries with similar starting positions. Along with efficient macroeconomic management, a key lesson from the Botswana experience is ensuring that economic growth translates into tangible social benefits for all. It means that growth needs to create jobs and incomes and that it must extend to the poorest in society. It also means that growth must lead to improvements in public services, particularly in health and education. This is not easy and in rural communities in Botswana, poverty remains at unacceptably high levels. For a number of reasons, many African countries continue to rely on the export of primary commodities rather than value addition and diversification of the economic base. The resultant capital-intensive growth has little direct effect on employment levels and few linkages to employment-intensive sectors such as agriculture. Thus, it is no wonder that despite years of strong economic growth, poverty remains so pervasive in so many resource-rich countries on the continent.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[21.- According to the article, one of the most important reasons for Botswana’s success is that;]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) It has a history of political stability]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) The advantages of economic growth have reached many people]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) It has a large supply of diamonds and a growing diamond industry]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) Poverty has been eliminated]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[22.- The article implies that to improve their situation, African countries need to;]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) Attract more foreign investors]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) Develop their agricultural sectors]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) Export more commodities]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) Provide more jobs]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="17">
	<Text><![CDATA[Global warming has already harmed the world’s food production and has driven up food prices by as much as 20% over recent decades, new research has revealed. The drop in the productivity of crop plants around the world was not caused by changes in rainfall but was because higher temperatures can cause dehydration, prevent pollination and lead to slowed photosynthesis.                                                                                                                                                             Lester Brown, president of the Earth Policy Institute, said the findings indicate a turning point: “Agriculture as it exists today evolved over 11,000 years of reasonably stable climate, but that climate system is no more. Adaptation is difficult because our knowledge of the future is not strong enough to drive new investments”, he said. “So we just keep going, hoping for the best.” The scientists say their work shows how crucial it is to find ways to adapt farming to a warmer world, to ensure that rises in global population are matched by rising food production. “It is vital,” said Wolfram Schlenker, one of the research team. “If we continue to have the same seed varieties and temperatures continue to rise, then food prices will rise further. Addressing that is the big question.”]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[23.- Food production has been negatively affected by;]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) Higher rainfall]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) Lower rainfall]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) Increased warmth]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) A drop in temperatures]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[24.- In the future, it will be important to;]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) Replace existing seed varieties with new ones]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) Try to adapt crop production to new climatic conditions]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) Reduce worldwide food prices]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) Direct investments in agriculture to largely populated areas]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="18">
	<Text><![CDATA[Green, incredibly alcoholic and some say mind-altering-these are the qualities that led to absinthe being banned in France almost 100 years ago. But all that’s about to change, after the government voted to allow sales of the drink nicknamed the “green fairy”.                                                      “I will not be seen as a drug addict anymore,” says Clement Arnoux, an absinthe drinker. The green, anise-flavoured spirit is associated with many of the country’s most famous and esteemed artists and writers but it was banned in France in 1915 for its alleged harmful effect. Later, the rule was relaxed, allowing the drink to be sold as long as it was not called absinthe, and instead labelled “a spirit made from extracts of the absinthe plant.” Now the ban is expected to be lifted entirely any day now, after the French Senate voted in favour of the move in mid-April. While drinkers like Clement Arnoux are relieved that the stigma of illegality has gone, not everyone sees the change of law as cause for celebration. Absinthe is usually around 60 or 70% alcohol, though it is not designed to be drunk neat, but mixed instead with water. For some, the drink’s high proof is part of its appeal. Young people are “always looking for something more,” says Laurent Legay, who works with people with drink problems.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[25.- The plan to legalize absinthe in France;]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) Has caused protests]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) Has been greeted with enthusiasm everywhere]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) Has met with a mixed reaction]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) Was initiated by artists and writers]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[26.- Previously in France;]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) Absinthe was never been sold legally]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) Absinthe was sold under special conditions]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) The sale of absinthe caused an increase in alcoholism]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) Absinthe was drunk straight]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="19">
	<Text><![CDATA[Several months ago, parts of the Amazon rainforest were in the grip of one of the most severe droughts on record. Rivers levels were at historic lows and the impact on wildlife was severe. The number of pink river dolphins in a remote part of the Peruvian Amazon dropped by nearly half in October compared with 2009, as the level of the Samiria River, a major tributary of the Amazon, fell. Along a 20km stretch of the river, a population of 250 declined to about 140.But now a team of conservation experts working in the region has found that many species have recovered more quickly than expected. This includes the pink dolphins, which, according to surveys conducted in March, have seen their numbers increased by nearly 10%, compared to the same period last year, prior to the drought. The number of grey dolphins is also up from March 2010 – by 30%. The research is being carried out in a national reserve in the Amazon. “This reserve is flooded forest, where we get high levels and low levels in the rivers every year,” says Dr. Bodmer. “But the 2010 drought and the record floods the previous year were much worse.” Now the water levels are extremely high again and local officials have declared a state of emergency. “We are being hit on both sides – extremely high levels of water or droughts,” says Dr. Bodmer.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[27.- According to the article;]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) The population of pink dolphins increased more rapidly after the drought]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) The population of pink dolphins increased more rapidly before the drought]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) The pink dolphin has been listed as an endangered species]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) The number of grey dolphins has decreased]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[28.- It is stated in the article that the Amazon Rainforest;]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) Suffers a drought every year]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) Rarely suffers flooding]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) Suffered its worst drought in 2009]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) Regularly suffers droughts and floods]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="20">
	<Text><![CDATA[She is the embodiment of modern Thai youth, dressed in flip flops, T-shirt and shorts and sipping an iced coffee with friends after university lectures. But 20-year-old Kanthoop is not just another university student. She has been spat at, publicly denigrated, threatened by police and faces up to 15 years in jail for little more, she says, than “having opinions.” To understand why Kanthoop might be so vilified is to understand Thai society. Twice a day time stands still in this nation of 69 million as the national anthem sputters out of public loudspeakers and everyone stands in silent salute. The routine testifies to the adoration Thai people feel for both their nation and their king. But that reverence is backed up by the world’s strictest pro-monarchy regulations, which sentences anyone who insults, defames or threatens the king to three to fifteen years imprisonment. Opponents argue that the law, known as Article 112, prevents healthy dialogue and is being used as a political tool to stifle dissent. Human rights groups, as well as the U.S, E.U. and U.N, have voiced concern over the way the law is used.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[29.- Which of the following is true?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) Thai people commonly criticize their king]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) Some organizations are disturbed by Article 112]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) Kanthoop has been sentenced to jail]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) Article 112 has been used to promote discussions]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[30.- What is stated in the report regarding Thai society?]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) It venerates its monarchy]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) It is hostile to outsiders]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) It doesn’t value its youth]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) Outsiders don’t understand it]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
</exam>
