<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?><exam id_exam="7" title="Departamento de Idiomas. Escuela de Guerra | INGLÉS" fecha="EXAMEN DE EMID/2012" tipo="Normal">
<intro1><![CDATA[En las sucesivas presentaciones usted encontrará preguntas de relacionadas con el texto redactado.]]></intro1>
<intro2><![CDATA[Después de leer y comprender el texto presentado deberá responder a una de las preguntas de la parte inferior.]]></intro2>
<intro3><![CDATA[Gracias por su colaboración. A continuación podrá <strong>imprimir</strong> las respuestas que han sido seleccionadas, o bien imprimirlas en un archivo <strong>pdf</strong> para su entrega al profesor correspondiente.]]></intro3>
<tiempoGlobal><![CDATA[75]]></tiempoGlobal>
<timeOver><![CDATA[Su tiempo ha terminado. Pulse finalizar e imprima sus respuestas]]></timeOver>
<user id= "1">LABRADO GOMEZ, CARLOS TIM: 51358887#</user>

<user id= "2">LAGUNA PEREZ, JAVIER TIM: 51652408#</user>

<user id= "3">CAP TOVAR HERNÁNDEZ, GERARDO TIM: 09279594#</user>

<user id= "4">MERINO TORO, LA BEGO TIM: 52104944#</user>

<user id= "5">TCOL. D. ANTONIO PIÑA SANCHEZ TIM: 43012165#</user>

<user id= "6">TCOL. D. ANGEL FERNANDEZ TUR TIM: 45068182#</user>

<user id= "7">T TE. D. ANDRES TORRES CASO TIM: 28800128#</user>

<user id= "8">CAP. ART.  JOSE  FRANCISCO   CAMPOS  BARBERO TIM: 06965997#</user>

<user id= "9">CAP. CAB.  GABRIEL     ECHEVERRIA  URQUIZU TIM: 15992562#</user>

<user id= "10">CAP. ABSTO.  MANUEL  JOSE    CEREZO       LOPEZ TIM: 30499977#</user>

<user id= "11">JAVIER CANDAU ROMERO TIM: 28696353#</user>

<user id= "12">TCOL. ANGEL MURILLO GÓMEZ TIM: 50701438#</user>

<user id= "13">CTE. D. JOSÉ ALFONSO ROMÁN BIENES TIM: 11735404#</user>

<user id= "14">TCOL. D. FRANCISCO JOSÉ LUGO PÉREZ TIM: 03824117#</user>

<user id= "15">TCOL. D. BALTASAR BONILLA MORALES TIM: 78074909#</user>

<user id= "16">TCOL. D. PABLO FERNANDO LESTAU MORELL TIM: 31648311#</user>

<user id= "17">CTE. D. MANUEL CARRASCO GÓMEZ TIM: 50843117#</user>

<user id= "18">CTE. D. AGUSTÍN FÉLIX AHEDO PELLITERO TIM: 21500338#</user>

<user id= "19">CAP. D. ANTONIO Mª CLARET IBÁÑEZ TARRADELLAS TIM: 33934211#</user>

<user id= "20">CTE. D. FRANCISCO GÓMEZ PAREDES TIM: 32678655#</user>

<user id= "21">CTE. D. BONIFACIO DE LA VIUDA LOZANO TIM: 09259803#</user>

<user id= "22">CAP. D. JUAN JERÓNIMO VILLALÓN CARBELLIDO TIM: 75757745#</user>

<user id= "23">CAP. D. ÁNGEL LUIS PIÑEIRO BUSTABAD TIM: 32633576#</user>

<user id= "24">CAP. D. PEDRO GARCÍA AGUADO TIM: 00379813#</user>

<user id= "25">CTE. D. DANIEL DONOSO RODRÍGUEZ TIM: 07525490#</user>

<user id= "26">CAP. D. MIGUEL A. ESTEVE AGUILAR TIM: 73770475#</user>

<user id= "27">TTE. D. JOSÉ OCTAVIO BOIRA MORENO TIM: 52887029#</user>

<user id= "28">TTE. D. CARLOS CLARAMONTE MARZO TIM: 72985673#</user>

<user id= "29">TTE. D. ALBERTO RUÍZ BIELSA TIM: 03913140#</user>

<user id= "30">TTE. D. ENRIQUE SÁNCHEZ DÍAZ TIM: 44352647#</user>

<user id= "31">TTE. D. JOAQUÍN PELLEGRÍN GAYÁN TIM: 72998617#</user>

<user id= "32">TCOL. D. SANTIAGO ÁLVAREZ HERRERO TIM: 09758017#</user>

<user id= "33">CAP. D. LEOPOLDO SANTOS SANTOS TIM: 07512351#</user>

<user id= "34">CAP. D. LUIS MARTÍNEZ THOMAS TIM: 09419326#</user>

<user id= "35">TCOL. D. RODOLFO MARTÍNEZ AZOFRA TIM: 32033891#</user>

<user id= "36">CTE. D. DARÍO DE JULIÁN FRÍAS TIM: 29119215#</user>

<user id= "37">CTE. D. JAVIER VÁZQUEZ HERMOSO TIM: 03457112#</user>

<user id= "38">TCOL. D. ALBERTO JAVIER GARCÍA ROMERA TIM: 24225777#</user>

<user id= "39">TCOL. D. PABLO MORA BURBANO TIM: 50828592#</user>

<user id= "40">CTE. D. MIGUEL DUEÑAS GONZÁLEZ TIM: 11821590#</user>

<user id= "41">TCOL. D. BENJAMÍN RIVED LEDESMA TIM: 25140809#</user>

<user id= "42">TCOL. D. CARLOS GALLEGO REMIRO TIM: 25442191#</user>

<user id= "43">CTE. D. ÁNGEL TOMÉ CARRILLO TIM: 45279892#</user>

<user id= "44">CTE. D. JOSÉ MANUEL FERNÁNDEZ MELÓN TIM: 09337260#</user>

<user id= "45">TCOL. D. JULIO JAVIER CARDERO ESCOS TIM: 13113534#</user>

<user id= "46">TTE. D. FERNANDO VIDALES BERROYA TIM: 51460093#</user>

<user id= "47">CTE. D. RODRIGO JOSÉ HERNÁNDEZ NAVARRO TIM: 29113542#</user>

<user id= "48">CAP. D. PEDRO ANTONIO MARTÍNEZ IRANZO TIM: 11846830#</user>

<user id= "49">CAP. D. CONSUELO DELAGE GARCÍA DE ÁNGULO TIM: 47768761#</user>

<user id= "50">TTE. D. VÍCTOR MONREAL GUMIEL TIM: 29133751#</user>

<user id= "51">COR. D. JOSÉ MANUEL SIABA PORTELA TIM: 33246623#</user>

<user id= "52">TCOL. D. JOSÉ ANTONIO ARAUZO MARTÍNEZ TIM: 13117909#</user>

<user id= "53">TCOL. D. MARCOS ÁNGEL SANZ OBERBERGER TIM: 25143730#</user>

<user id= "54">CTE. D. JUAN CARLOS MILLÓN PINTOS TIM: 35324071#</user>

<user id= "55">CAP. D. ÁLVARO LOMAS CARDONA TIM: 25079402#</user>

<user id= "56">TTE. D. ESTEBAN VICENTE BOISSEAU TIM: 29170771#</user>

<user id= "57">TTE. D. FRANCISCO JOSÉ OSUNA LOZANO TIM: 41507482#</user>

<user id= "58">TTE. D. SERGIO VILLAESCUSA GONZÁLEZ TIM: 78918065#</user>

<user id= "59">TTE. D. JOSÉ ANTONIO PEREA ÁLVAREZ TIM: 75890640#</user>

<user id= "60">TTE. D. MARIO LOZANO BENITO TIM: 20262808#</user>

<user id= "61">BG. D. ANTONIO DURAN CARRILLO DURAN CARRILLO TIM: 02872622#</user>

<user id= "62">BG. D. MOISES BARRANCO SERRANOS BARRANCO SERRANOS TIM: 25456698#</user>

<user id= "63">BG. D. MANUEL MARIA GARCIA VICENTE GARCIA VICENTE TIM: 30577814#</user>

<user id= "64">BG. D. JOSE JAVIER  ALOS VELERT  ALOS VELERT TIM: 22553148#</user>

<user id= "65">BG. D. JOSE LUIS  SALGADO DE DIEGO  SALGADO DE DIEGO TIM: 05264084#</user>

<user id= "66">BG. D. GABRIEL MARTINEZ SECALL MARTINEZ SECALL TIM: 38113350#</user>

<user id= "67">BG. D. JOSE LUIS DE LAS PEÑAS PLANA DE LAS PEÑAS PLANA TIM: 00413049#</user>

<user id= "68">SBTE. D. JACINTO JOSE CALABOR ALONSO CALABOR ALONSO TIM: 22539187#</user>

<user id= "69">SGTO 1º. D. JUAN IGNACIO HERNANDEZ LEAL HERNANDEZ LEAL TIM: 29115714#</user>

<user id= "70">BG. D. ANTONIO PEREZ GOMEZ PEREZ GOMEZ TIM: 27297055#</user>

<user id= "71">SGTO 1º. D. JAVIER IRANZO GARCIA IRANZO GARCIA TIM: 25423055#</user>

<user id= "72">SGTO 1º. D. FELIX ORTEGA PRIETO ORTEGA PRIETO TIM: 04595120#</user>

<user id= "73">SGTO 1º. D. FRANCISCO POLO GONZÁLEZ POLO GONZÁLEZ TIM: 30817212#</user>

<user id= "74">SGTO 1º. D. MANUEL  BARBOSA ROVIGO BARBOSA ROVIGO TIM: 10900268#</user>

<user id= "75">BG. D. JOAQUIN GONZALEZ LOPEZ GONZALEZ LOPEZ TIM: 50708673#</user>

<user id= "76">BG. D. FRANCISCO JESUS PEÑA DIAZ PEÑA DIAZ TIM: 33502596#</user>

<user id= "77">BG. D. CARLOS TIMOTEO VEGA MARTIN VEGA MARTIN TIM: 11935408#</user>

<user id= "78">BG. D. LUIS ALBERTO GUERRA SANZO GUERRA SANZO TIM: 09797900#</user>

<user id= "79">BG. D. LUIS  CAMPILLO BAREZ CAMPILLO BAREZ TIM: 45075011#</user>

<user id= "80">SGTO. D. JOSE ANTONIO CACERES BAENA CACERES BAENA TIM: 50988746#</user>

<user id= "81">CTE. JUARROS LAFUENTE, BERNARDINO TIM: 13304139#</user>

<user id= "82">CTE. GOMEZ RAMOS, ANTONIO VICTORIANO TIM: 50092021#</user>

<user id= "83">CTE. PEREZ DE LUCAS, CESAR TIM: 03469246#</user>

<user id= "84">SGT1º. GATON MIGUELSANZ, RAUL TIM: 12379098#</user>

<user id= "85">TCOL. CORPAS RUIZ, ANTONIO TIM: 30498869#</user>

<user id= "86">CTE. GARCES MENDUIÑA, JOSE MIGUEL TIM: 30806026#</user>

<user id= "87">TCOL. GUASCH AGUILAR, MARIANO TIM: 22546098#</user>

<user id= "88">CTE. HERRANZ SANZ, JAVIER TIM: 51075280#</user>

<user id= "89">TCOL. MORENO SANTOS, MANUEL TIM: 31234018#</user>

<user id= "90">CTE. SAN SEGUNDO CAMPO, MIGUEL ANGEL TIM: 06568918#</user>

<user id= "91">CTE. VALCAZAR ALONSO, CESAR TIM: 12758488#</user>

<user id= "92">CTE. MARTIN HERRERA, RAUL TIM: 50701152#</user>

<user id= "93">CTE. MUÑIZ BASCUAS, JOSE DANIEL TIM: 52683894#</user>

<user id= "94">CTE. NIEVAS GUTIERREZ, JOSE MIGUEL TIM: 24167228#</user>

<user id= "95">CTE. SANTE ABAL, MANUEL TIM: 52493903#</user>

<user id= "96">TCOL. DE LUCAS LOBO, RAFAEL TIM: 50416386#</user>

<user id= "97">CTE. GARCIA SERON, PEDRO JOSE TIM: 22988923#</user>

<user id= "98">CTE. MARQUEZ DE LA CALLEJA, FERNANDO TIM: 02902556#</user>

<user id= "99">SGT1º. MORENO HERRANZ, DANIEL TIM: 50189566#</user>

<user id= "100">CTE. RIVAS CASTEL, DANIEL TIM: 51684560#</user>

<user id= "101">STTE. D. JUAN FERNANDO SILVA MARTINEZ TIM: 08797742#</user>

<user id= "102">STTE. D. RAMON JIMENEZ HUESO TIM: 27264940#</user>

<user id= "103">STTE. D. ANDRES CARDEÑOSA RIVERO TIM: 01107556#</user>

<user id= "104">STTE. D. JUAN LUIS BERENGUER DE DIEGO TIM: 00804792#</user>

<user id= "105">STTE. D. JUAN JOSE INES DE DIEGO TIM: 14594214#</user>

<user id= "106">STTE. D. JOSE CAROLLO RAÑA TIM: 30552550#</user>

<user id= "107">STTE. D. ANGEL GALVEZ URREA TIM: 05170310#</user>

<user id= "108">BG. D. FRANCISCO JAVIER MARTINEZ GONZALEZ TIM: 50042602#</user>

<user id= "109">BG. D. SANTIAGO A. SERRANO DIAZ TIM: 25073773#</user>

<user id= "110">BG. D. JUAN VALLEJO RUIZ TIM: 52542807#</user>

<user id= "111">BG. D. PEDRO JOSE MANCHEÑO CARPINTERO TIM: 05385260#</user>

<user id= "112">BG. D. JESUS ANGEL MUÑOZ ZAPATA TIM: 50164553#</user>

<user id= "113">BG. D. JAIME SANCHEZ ALONSO TIM: 11772183#</user>

<user id= "114">BG. D. JOSE ANTONIO CHAVES ARIZA TIM: 25069497#</user>

<user id= "115">BG. D. AURELIO SALVADOR LUJAN TIM: 04578156#</user>

<user id= "116">BG. D. LUIS ANTONIO GOMEZ LOPEZ TIM: 32767933#</user>

<user id= "117">BG. D. FRANCISCO JAVIER AVELLANEDA GARCIA TIM: 45274051#</user>

<user id= "118">BG. D. MANUEL RUIZ FERNANDEZ TIM: 07521230#</user>

<user id= "119">SGTO 1º. D. SANTIAGO CRESPO GUTIERREZ TIM: 31254450#</user>

<user id= "120">SGTO 1º. D. ANTONIO CUADRADO TOLEDO TIM: 45283372#</user>

<user id= "121">SGTO 1º. D. ALONSO ANTONIO MORENO ALMAGRO TIM: 52816995#</user>

<user id= "122">SGTO 1º. D. FRANCISCO DIAZ ARRIERO TIM: 04194064#</user>

<user id= "123">SGTO 1º. D. VALENTIN RODOLFO SANTAMARIA GALEA TIM: 50454111#</user>

<user id= "124">SGTO 1º. D. FRANCISCO MANUEL VILLA MATEO TIM: 52693767#</user>

<user id= "125">SGTO 1º. D. LUIS UCETA GARCIA TIM: 52501920#</user>

<user id= "126">SGTO 1º. D. ENRIQUE SANCHO DEL BARRIO TIM: 13786571#</user>

<user id= "127">SGTO 1º. D. JOSE Mª HERNANDEZ ALDEHUELO TIM: 02898566#</user>

<user id= "128">SGTO 1º. D. JUAN CARLOS GONZALEZ VAZQUEZ TIM: 16300776#</user>

<user id= "129">SGTO 1º. D. JOSE PIGUEIRAS FERNANDEZ TIM: 33996143#</user>

<user id= "130">SGTO 1º. D. JOSE ROMERO TORRENTE TIM: 32662507#</user>

<user id= "131">SGTO 1º. D. FRANCISCO HUERTA ESTRUGA TIM: 03861914#</user>

<user id= "132">SGTO 1º. D. BENJAMIN CANTILLO MORENO TIM: 52468216#</user>

<user id= "133">SGTO 1º. D. RAFAEL BAENA LOPEZ TIM: 31864651#</user>

<user id= "134">SGTO 1º. D. MANUEL BARANGUA AZNAR TIM: 34857955#</user>

<user id= "135">SGTO 1º. D. J IGNACIO SANCHEZ DE VENA TIM: 13153854#</user>

<user id= "136">SGTO 1º. D. JUAN A GUTIERREZ SOBRADO TIM: 28952241#</user>

<user id= "137">SGTO 1º. D. ALBERTO COLOMO LOECHES TIM: 08998551#</user>

<user id= "138">SGTO 1º. D. JOSE PINO CAMACHO TIM: 25587217#</user>

<user id= "139">SGTO 1º. D. EDUARDO JOSE ALVAREZ MONTES TIM: 11427316#</user>

<user id= "140">SGTO 1º. D. SERGIO CALZADO PEREZ TIM: 09804963#</user>

<user id= "141">SGTO 1º. D. JUAN ANTONIO GALLEGO RUIZ TIM: 80063549#</user>

<user id= "142">SGTO 1º. D. MARCO ANTONIO ANTUNEZ DIAZ TIM: 28758203#</user>

<user id= "143">SGTO 1º. D. JOAQUIN MIGUEL MIRANDA MARTINEZ TIM: 34859515#</user>

<user id= "144">SGTO 1º. D. DAVID MARTINEZ HERNANDEZ TIM: 30835741#</user>

<user id= "145">SGTO 1º. D. DAVID VICENTE BARROSO TIM: 12388692#</user>

<user id= "146">SGTO. D. MANUEL SAEZ CORCHERO TIM: 08878219#</user>

<user id= "147">SGTO. D. PEDRO MARTIN DE ARCO TIM: 45300855#</user>

<user id= "148">SGTO. D. CARLOS TERRIZA TORRES TIM: 05699503#</user>

<question nquest="1">
	<Text><![CDATA[Csilla from Hungary tells about how she found her cat. I first saw Mandula last summer along a busy road. She was begging people for food. The poor cat was all skin and bones at that time. She was starving. Mandula was also pregnant. Thus, I decided to look after her immediately. Two weeks after I brought her into my home, Mandula gave birth to six beautiful and playful kittens. Those kittens have grown up and are living in different homes. And, Mandula – whose name means “almond” in Hungarian — is now a happy cat who likes to watch television with me every evening.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[1.- According to the text, …]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) Mandula was quite fat when she was found.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) Csilla now has 7 cats living with her.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) Mandula likes eating almonds and watching TV.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) Csilla found homes for all of Mandula’s kittens.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="2">
	<Text><![CDATA[A Military Operation. The store force consisted of both naval and army elements as the destroyer was landing troops, equipment and supplies. The whole operation was carried out at night, without a moon and showing no lights for security reasons. Each man had been drilled to do his work precisely and without being able to see more than a few yards. Silence was also a key element, so unavoidable noises were muffled as far as was possible.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[2.-What happened the night of the operation?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) The landing could be easily seen and heard by the enemy.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) They tried to land the men and the equipment without being seen.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) They had muffled the equipment so that no light could be seen.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) They used secret codes so as to surprise the enemy.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="3">
	<Text><![CDATA[News about The Iron Curtain. According to a report in Germany’s Der Spiegel magazine, the land once known as “the Iron Curtain” may be protected. The Iron Curtain was a term used to describe the border between Eastern and Western Europe from 1945 to 1990. In Germany, the Iron Curtain stretched 1,400 kilometers and was covered in wire and mines. Although this land was uninhabitable for humans, it was a good place for
wildlife –including black storks, otters and bats — to exist. Now the governments of 16 states in Germany may decide to protect this area by not
allowing the development of roads and buildings in it.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[3.- Which statement is true?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) Some land mines have been found near the Iron Curtain.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) There has been a proposal to protect the Iron Curtain from demolition.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) The land around the Iron Curtain is home to many types of wildlife.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) Some German states want to develop the Iron Curtain area.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="4">
	<Text><![CDATA[Horoscope: Taurus. The sign Taurus is ruled by Venus. Physically it is related to the throat. It is said to have a feminine nature, and is therefore more passive and receptive in its energy expression. Taurus is an Earth sign and as such is connected with fruitfulness and stability. A planet placed in this sign will be a stabilizing influence and manifest its energy in a steadfast and determined manner. Taurus is also a fixed sign, and this means that once a course is embarked on, it is rarely deviated from. Maintenance and care of existing conditions over long periods of time, and a reluctance to initiate change, are qualities of this sign.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[4.- Which of these statements is true about a Taurus person?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) He/she changes plans easily.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) He/she is domineering.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) He/she is firm.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) He/she has a masculine nature.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="5">
	<Text><![CDATA[The Green Jacket. You might not consider a green jacket to be among the most desirable fashion items. Nevertheless, the world’s best golfers will be trying to win a green jacket this weekend at the Masters Tournament in Augusta, Georgia. In addition to receiving a couple hundred thousand dollars in prize money, the winner becomes an honorary member of the Augusta National Golf Club and receives a green jacket. The winner gets to keep the green jacket for a year, then he returns it to the club to wear whenever he visits. It is traditional for the winner of the previous year’s tournament to present the jacket to the present winner.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[5.- Which statement is true about winners of the Masters Golf Tournament?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) They receive a check for $20,000 in prize money.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) They receive a green jacket which they keep for life.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) They present a green jacket to the next year’s winner.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) They can wear their green jacket to other golf tournaments.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="6">
	<Text><![CDATA[Asparagus with Alioli.-Ingredients.- 2 asparagus bunches, or 20 spears, 4 medium to large garlic cloves, salt to taste, 2 egg yolks, 1 ½ tbsp fresh lemon juice, 1 cup extra virgin Spanish olive oil.Preparation.- For alioli sauce, peel and mince garlic with salt to make a paste. Add egg yolks to
paste and whisk. Slowly pour in olive oil until a creamy sauce forms. Add a dash of lemon juice and blend. For asparagus, trim off the bottoms. Steam for five to eight minutes. Remove spears from steamer and drain, allowing them to cool. Finally, pour sauce over asparagus and serve. Remember in Spain it is traditional to eat asparagus with your fingers.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[6.- To prepare this dish you have to..]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) warm the alioli sauce.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) make a paste with the asparagus.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) add the alioli sauce before serving.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) fry the asparagus.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="7">
	<Text><![CDATA[Crossing Borders. Rudolf Karnis, aged 71, remembers the days when a holiday outside of his native Slovakia was filled with problems at the borders. During trips to neighboring countries, such as Hungary and Poland, Karnis and his family would have to stop for long periods at the border for customs control. “It is nothing like that anymore,” said Karnis, who, like millions of other Central Europeans, is travelling across borders without even having to stop. His countryman Peter Svancar, a civil engineer who works in Poland, agrees. “It is much more relaxing now when your train is not stopped at the borders and you do not have to show your passport all the time,” he said.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[7.- Which statement is true?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) Mr. Karnis used to have to wait to travel across borders.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) Central Europeans have to show their passports at borders.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) Mr. Karnis enjoys travelling with his neighbor on holidays.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) Rudolf Karnis and Peter Svancar both live in Poland.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="8">
	<Text><![CDATA[A News Story about an Incident at a Restaurant: Health and Sanitation Department Inspector Ralph Simmons says that if the manager of the restaurant hadn’t tried to cut costs by buying mushrooms from unlicensed sellers, he wouldn’t have sent all those people to the hospital with food poisoning last week. The restaurant manager was unavailable for comment but a spokesman for the restaurant said the victims had all recovered and offered his sincere apologies for the unfortunate incident.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[8.- Which statement is true?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) A health inspector closed a restaurant selling poison mushrooms.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) A restaurant manager’s attempt to save money caused a big problem.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) Several people became ill after eating mushrooms they collected.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) Several people have accused the manager of poisoning them.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="9">
	<Text><![CDATA[Biomass as a carbon-neutral energy source. As we struggle to meet our renewable-energy goals, we ought to embrace biomass. Biomass energy is positively carbon-neutral. Burning agricultural waste or forest residue to generate electricity releases no more carbon dioxide than if those materials simply decayed. Furthermore, biomass energy reduces the need to burn fossil fuels, and the less fossil fuel we burn the more we reduce our carbon footprint. But that hasn’t stopped fear-mongering aimed at denying biomass credit as a cleanenergy source. Claims that biomass energy is anything but carbon-neutral ignore the fact that not all carbon is created equal, at least in terms of the global carbon cycle. When fossil fuels are burned to produce energy, there is a net increase in carbon released to the atmosphere, because it takes carbon that was stored safely underground and adds it to the atmosphere. Biomass energy, however, deals with biogenic carbon - carbon that is already part of the atmospheric system. There’s no carbon added because the carbon in question is already part of the global-carbon cycle. So even if more carbon dioxide goes up a biomass-energy power-plant smokestack than a coal-fired power-plant smokestack, it’s OK because one is relatively harmless and the other relatively harmful. As regulators debate what should and shouldn’t be considered renewable energy sources, they should focus on encouraging investment to reduce emissions and our dependence on fossil fuels. Most of all, science should trump irrational fears. It’s time to give biomass the credit it is due.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[9.- According to the text, which of the following is true?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) Burning biomass produces more electricity than burning fossil fuels.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) There should be more credits available for funding biomass projects.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) Fears about the efficiency of biomass need to be considered.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) Replacing fossil fuels with biomass would reduce our carbon footprint.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[10.- Which of the following is NOT true?]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) The line between renewable and non-renewable energies is very thin.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) Carbon dioxide produced by burning biomass and fossil fuel cannot be equated.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) Biomass energy has become a cheap and competitive alternative fuel.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) Scientists need to study and clarify the benefits of biomass energy.]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="10">
	<Text><![CDATA[A journalist’s response to recent microbiology research: There are some things it is better just not to think about. Like the 10,000 bacteria you inhale with each breath in the average office building. Or the 10 million bacteria in each glass of tap water. Microbiologists have now added something else to the list of things too gross to contemplate: the deluge of bacteria that hit your face and flow deep into your lungs in the morning shower. This unwelcome peek behind the shower curtain has been provided by a group of microbiologists at the University of Colorado using a new type of test. Conventional tests depend on growing cultures of the bacteria to be identified, but because most species cannot be grown in the laboratory, a majority of bacterial species are missed. The new method examines the genetic material directly, without the need for culturing bacteria. As part of a project to measure microbes in the indoor human environment, they looked at shower water, in part because in showers bacteria are incorporated into fine droplets that can be breathed deep into the lungs. The bacteria get into shower heads from the water and build up there, so the dose is highest when the shower is first turned on. Running the water for 30 seconds before stepping in would mean fewer bacteria in one’s face. Also, the bacteria seem to find metal shower heads a less hospitable niche than plastic ones.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[11.- What was one conclusion of the article?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) New methods of testing have exposed much higher numbers of microbes in water and
air supplies than previously suspected.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) There are no effective ways to decrease the amount of bacteria you are exposed to in
the shower.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) Bacteria builds up over time, so the longer your shower, the more bacteria you are
exposed to.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) There are some simple steps you can take to greatly reduce the amount of bacteria
inhaled while in the shower.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[12.- What is the writer's opinion of this type of microbiological research?]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) He doesn't understand how someone could undertake this kind of disgusting research.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) Even though this type of research is important, we shouldn't think about it in our day to
day lives.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) We would be better off if scientists didn't undertake this kind of research because it just
makes us more paranoid.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) The research is rather pointless since so much of the bacteria can't be identified with
current techniques.]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="11">
	<Text><![CDATA[A film critic’s assessment of the "youth culture" in Hollywood: The 23-year old Shia LaBeouf, without meaning to do so, has become a metaphor for
how youth culture - after decades of elbowing its way to the forefront - now almost entirely dominates the culture itself. One day, he was a Disney kid, starring on cable’s "Even Stevens" and in the movie "Holes", and then suddenly, Steven Spielberg turned him into an action star in the latest "Indiana Jones" film. LaBeouf’s rise owes a great deal to his own charisma and charm, of course, but the actor’s ubiquity represents a slightly off-putting new paradigm in Hollywood: Young viewers want to see young stars, as they always have, but older viewers - the ones who can still be bothered to see movies in theaters - want to see young stars as well. The disturbing part is that those older audiences seem to have lost most of their interest in films about people their own age. Many recent "adult dramas" have flopped at the box office. And while a case can be made that those individual films had flaws that had nothing to do with their target demographic, their disappointing returns are endemic of a larger cultural trend wherein youth is valued above all else and maturity is, well, boring. For the studios, this winds up as a win-win; younger stars with shorter careers don’t cost as much as a older, more established stars. And when audiences vote with their dollars for the newcomers over the veterans, that ensures a healthier profit margin.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[13.- According to the article, what are some of the recent changes taking place in Hollywood?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) Young stars have come to expect the same treatment and paychecks as established
stars.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) Among older viewers, films starring young actors are still not as popular as adult
dramas.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) Some flawed films have proven to be very popular based on the appeal of LaBeouf.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) Adults' taste in films are now more aligned with those of younger viewers.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[14.- The writer of the article believes that:]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) LaBeouf is representative of a youth fad that will pass quickly.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) The failure of recent adult dramas to perform at the box office is clearly due to the
quality of the films themselves.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) LaBeouf and other young stars are displacing more talented actors because they are
so much in demand.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) LaBeouf and other young stars are displacing more talented actors because they are
so much in demand.]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="12">
	<Text><![CDATA[The following is an article about the possibility of providing health insurance to illegal immigrants in the U.S.: The question of giving health insurance to undocumented workers is ethically murky and politically impossible. Some people argue that if we’re hiring illegals to, say, shingle our roofs, we have a moral obligation to care for them if they fall off. But more people simply want them out of the country. Given that illegal immigrants have, by definition, broken our laws, it makes sense that large numbers of upstanding citizens oppose any measure that would encourage more foreigners to sneak into America or make their lives easier once they’re here. The only problem? From a purely economic standpoint, insuring illegal immigrants makes a lot of sense - and not just for them, but for everyone. Immigrants typically arrive in America during their prime working years and tend to be younger and healthier than the rest of the U.S. population. As a result, health-care expenditures for the average immigrant are lower than for a native-born American citizen with similar characteristics. It stands to reason that including the relatively healthy,relatively employable and largely uninsured illegal population in some sort of universal health-care system would be a boon rather than a burden. "Insurance in principle has to cover the average medical cost of all the people it’s serving," explains a professor of health policy. "So if you add cheaper people to the pool, like immigrants, you reduce the average cost." More undocumented workers, in other words, means lower premiums for everyone. And, since most illegal workers stay only long enough to save enough money to support their families in their home
countries, they leave before becoming a burden on the system.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[15.- According to the article, which of the following statements are true?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) Many U.S. citizens have recently begun demanding insurance for illegal workers,
especially those working dangerous jobs.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) Having illegal workers take part in a universal care system would likely benefit the
whole system.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) It makes financial sense to develop a separate system of health care solely for illegal
immigrants.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) Importing legal workers from other countries would be more beneficial than insuring
illegal workers already in the U.S.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[16.- Which of the following statements best reflects the writer's opinion?]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) Insuring illegal workers is a good idea as long as we oblige them to leave before they
get old.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) Insuring illegal workers would only encourage more to come to the U.S., which over
time, would burden the system.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) The fact that many of the workers are criminals makes the plan politically untenable.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) Though a good idea, his plan to insure illegal immigrants is unlikely to ever take place.]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="13">
	<Text><![CDATA[The decline of handwriting: Recently, two journalists wrote a newspaper article about the decline of handwriting. By now it’s well-known: most kids - what with computers and text messages - can no longer write by hand, except in laboured capital letters. The crisis began with the advent of the ballpoint pen. Early ballpoints were very messy and if, immediately after writing, you ran your finger over the last few words, a smudge inevitably appeared. So, people no longer felt much interest in writing well, since handwriting, when produced with a ballpoint, even a clean one, no longer had soul, style or personality. Why should we regret the passing of good handwriting? The capacity to write well and quickly on a keyboard encourages rapid thought, and often the spell-checker will underline a misspelling. However, handwriting teaches us to control our hands and encourages hand-eye coordination. Writing by hand obliges us to compose the phrase mentally before writing it down. Thanks to the resistance of pen and paper, it does make one slow down and think. It’s true that kids will write more and more on computers and cellphones.
Nonetheless, humanity has learned to rediscover as sports and aesthetic pleasures many things that civilisation had eliminated as unnecessary. People no longer travel on horseback but some go to a riding school; motor yachts exist but many people are devoted to sailing; there are tunnels but many still enjoy walking or climbing Alpine passes. It would be a good thing if parents sent kids off to handwriting schools so they could
take part in competitions and tournaments - not only to acquire grounding in what is beautiful, but also for psychomotor wellbeing.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[17.- What is the writer's opinion about the decline of handwriting skills?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) The rise of computers and cellphones should take most of the blame for the decline.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) Nothing good comes out of learning to write on computers and text messages.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) The unreliability of early ballpoint pens discouraged people from learning to write well.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) The skills improved by learning to handwrite are more useful than those improved by
learning to type.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[18.- What are the writer's thoughts about the future of handwriting?]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) Handwriting, like many other skills in human history, will likely pass into obscurity.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) Handwriting will become a hobby that people will develop despite its anachronism.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) Sending children to handwriting schools would be useful only if other subjects were
taught.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) Like horseback riding and sailing, handwriting will likely develop into a pastime for the
elite.]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="14">
	<Text><![CDATA[A Canadian journalist’s appraisal of the relationship between the U.S. and Canada: Anti-Americanism has been Canada’s defining intellectual ailment for generations. Not the fire-breathing hatred felt in some parts of the world, or even the elitist sneer directed westward from across the Atlantic; it was always a more neighborly, eyerolling disapproval that reached its zenith under George W. Bush. The Canadian press bristled with shrill attacks on the neoconservative agenda. That was then. Suddenly Canadian attitudes have matured at a breakneck pace - and not just because Americans elected Barack Obama (though of course that’s a part of it). Canadian anti-Americanism is fueled, fundamentally, by envy and fear. But
over the past year, the United States has been laid low by a devastating financial collapse. Canada’s economy, on the other hand, has escaped relatively unscathed. Its banking and real-estate sectors have been models of well-regulated stability compared with their American counterparts. The World Economic Forum proclaimed Canada to have the soundest banking system on the entire planet. Whatever Canadians think about the direction of the United States under Obama, few of them are still worried about American billionaires buying up their country lock, stock, and
barrel. America has long been lampooned by Canadian social critics as a throwback to a cruel, bygone era of laissez-faire capitalism. But under the Democratic Congress and White House, the government’s role in the economy has surged. The overall result is that the Canadian and American approaches to the size of government are beginning to converge. This healing trend comes primarily as an unintended effect of recent developments in Washington and on Wall Street. But it’s also a sign that Canada has grown up.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[19.- Which of the following statements is true?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) Canadians still remain skeptical of the U.S.’s governing style.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) Canadians generally support their American counterparts.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) Canadians have softened their views towards the U.S.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) Canadians have placed great expectations in America’s new government.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[20.- Which of the following statements best reflects the writer's opinion?]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) Canadians share the same anti-American sentiments as those of other countries.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) The capitalist market in America is just as cruel and outdated as it ever was.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) Canadians have begun shedding some of their fearful anti-Americanism.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) Canada's own financial disaster has caused them sympathy for the American plight.]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="15">
	<Text><![CDATA[Global warming and population control: As related by the Washington Post, two recent studies have pointed out that the real culprit for global warming isn’t cars or coal plants, it’s us. There are too many humans on planet Earth. The cheapest cure is contraception, according to a study
released by the London School of Economics, which points out that each $7 spent on family planning over the next four decades would reduce carbon-dioxide emissionsby more than a ton. Achieving the same result with low-carbon technologies would cost at least $32. I think I’ve got the answer to climate change: a cap-and-trade program for babies., OK, maybe not. But the notion is only a little sillier than the solution being promoted by the London School. Their model for fighting climate change by promoting birth control in the Third World ignores the fact that such programs almost never work. There are many reasons for the population explosion, but most of them come down to one factor: poverty. Women in poor countries have almost no power over reproductive decisions and are encouraged to have more children in places where infant mortality is high, so they go from one pregnancy to the next. Programs to promote condoms aren’t going to change any of this; if you want to lower birth rates
you have to reduce poverty. That means investing in development for poor countries. Of course, with development come higher greenhouse gas emissions. But there is a solution for this new problem as well: make these societies “grow green” with the help of new clean-energy technologies developed in the U.S. and other rich countries.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[21.- It can be concluded from the article that:]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) solutions for global warming must be developed in the First World and disseminated to
developing countries.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) contraception campaigns in the developing world will solve the problem of global
warming.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) a cap-and-trade program for babies could be a viable solution to curb population
growth.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) in poor countries, women control the number of children that a family has.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[22.- Which of following opinions on how to prevent global warming in the developing world best
reflects that of the author:]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) Limits should be palced on the number of children per family in those places.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) The developed nations must restrict their industrialization.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) They must develope using new, cleaner technologies.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) Contraception and education campaigns should reduce the population before they
industrialize]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="16">
	<Text><![CDATA[A journalist’s investigation into California’s financial situation: California, the state that once boasted the best schools and highways in America
now has some of the worst. Its healthcare is ranked lowest of all the 50 states; its public finances are a disaster. Year after year, its legislature has failed to agree a budget. Its deficits make Italy look like a paragon of fiscal prudence. The government of one of the most richly endowed territories on earth, a crucible of innovation and the eighth largest economy in the world, is broke. Why has California got into such a mess? Some analysts say: "Too much democracy!" In California’s eccentric version of direct democracy, all kinds of extravagant public spending are mandated by initiatives, proposed by anyone who can gather enough signatures, and passed by a simple majority of those who bother to vote on them, while the state’s revenue-gathering possibilities are curbed by the same method. Yet it’s not fair to blame all this on government of the people by the people. Rather, California shows how such experiments in direct democracy can be perverted. For this framework of initiatives was established by self-styled progressives in the early 20th century to curb the power of the railway bosses and bring power to the people. A hundred years later, it is today’s diverse special-interest groups - not just billionaires and businesses but also powerful public service unions - who play the system to feather their own nests or further their own fads. They hire hands to collect signatures on their chosen initiative, and use advertising muscle to whip in the votes. The result is that the conflicting interests bring the government to a standstill.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[23.- Which of these statements, according to the article, is NOT true?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) Special-interest groups abuse the system to further their own goals.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) The same progressives who created the system have, over time, crippled it to the point
of ineffectiveness.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) California´s system means that anyone can propose a spending bill as long as they
have enough public support.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) California´s system of democracy encourages spending while making it difficult to raise
money.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[24.- Which of the following statements best reflects the writer's opinion?]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) Though the system had admirable goals at its creation, nowadays it is ineffective.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) Unions should have done more to prevent rich people and business from taking
advantage of the system.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) The idea of the initiative system was flawed from the start.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) California is an example of how the power of demoncracy works in practice.]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="17">
	<Text><![CDATA[A UK journalist’s opinion on the opening of an expensive veterinary health centre: Humans are a selfish species - we breed and domesticate millions of animals for our own purposes of companionship and control, and then we complain if "too much" money is spent on their medical treatment. It doesn’t seem too much to have one state of the art veterinary centre for animals serving the whole of the UK. All modern medical treatment is expensive. The £15 million needed to operate the centre is a lot of money, but it pales in comparison with the annual National Health
Service budget of £110 billion. We abandon, neglect, maltreat, and euthanize (for our own convenience) hundreds of thousands every year. Our use of companion animals comes at a high cost to them in terms of their welfare and premature death. It only seems reasonable that we should pay something back for all their love and devotion. We need to bear in mind that these creatures wouldn’t exist if it wasn’t for us. Often I am asked to respond to this loaded question: "Is it right to have these facilities for animals while humans face waiting lists?" We could equally ask this loaded question: "Is it right to spend an annual NHS budget of £110 billion on humans when other sentient species, equally capable of suffering pain, fear, distress, anxiety, terror - domestic animals which we have brought into being and to whom we have a duty of care - are only given a tiny fraction
of the medical care they require?"]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[25.- Which of the following statements best reflects the writer’s opinion about the veterinarian
health centre?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) We must focus on issues of the mistreatment of animals before opening such an
expensive health centre.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) The centre should be opened, but should not include facilities for euthanasia.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) Given the amount of money spent on the treatment of humans, we can afford to help
animals.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) The centre should be opened, but the money should not come from the NHS budget.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[26.- What does the writer believe about the moral relationship between humans and animals?]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) Even if animals didn´t feel the same emotional range as humans, we would still have to
care for them]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) It´s only acceptable to euthanize those animals which have been mistreated,
abandoned, or live in pain.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) It is immoral to spend money on expensive veterinarian facilities while many humans
are in need of health care.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) We must provide care for domesticated animals because we have made them
dependent on us.]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="18">
	<Text><![CDATA[The truthfulness of documentary films: A recent report on documentary films had a message for those who look to those films for guidance about matters as serious as business, politics, nature and the meaning of life: let the viewer beware. Based on anonymous interviews with 45 longform
documentary filmmakers, the study came to some conclusions that could shock those schooled in conventional journalistic ethics. The report found that documentarians, while they generally aspire to act honourably, often operate under ad hoc ethical codes. The craft tends to see itself as being bound less by the need to be accurate and fair than by a desire for social justice, to level the playing field between those who are perceived to be powerful and those who are not. That often means manipulating individual facts, sequences and meanings of images, said the report, if that might help viewers to grasp the documentary’s higher truth. Deception in pursuit of a good story is acceptable to some. For example, one documentarian
acknowledged letting film crew members break the legs of rabbits in order to get better shots of animals being hunted by others in the wild. Other filmmakers said that corporate executives and celebrities were entitled to less protection as interview subjects than more sympathetic individuals. "Everybody who makes a movie, documentary or otherwise, is motivated by passion and point of view", said one documentary filmmaker. "But, they are hindered by the need for access, financial resources and the realities of seeking an audience."]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[27.- According to what is stated in the article:]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) Documentary filmmakers have been unjustly accused of manipulating facts.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) The truth presented in documentary films may be more skewed than the viewer
expected.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) Documentary filmmakers are solely interested in presenting the facts and the higher
truth.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) The conventional ethics learned at the school of journalists was corroborated.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[28.- According to the article, which of the following statements is true?]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) Some documentary filmmmakers find it acceptable to manipulate small facts in the
name of social justice.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) Documentary filmmakers seeking an audience or funding should manipulate facts.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) Documentaries, which concern issues of social justice, have a greater responsibility to
be accurate.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) Filmmakers who are passionate about their subject matter shouldn't be restricted by
the truth.]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="19">
	<Text><![CDATA[A scientist’s appraisal of the state of space exploration: Neil Armstrong’s first small step for man was widely believed to be the start of a long
and glorious road to the stars. Forty years after the first Moon landing, the dream has faded. Astronauts have been stuck in low-Earth orbit, boldly going nowhere. American attempts to kick-start a new phase of lunar exploration have stalled amid the realisation that NASA´s budget is too small for the job. Clearly, some creative thinking is badly needed if humans are to have a future beyond Earth. Returning to the Moon may be worthy and attainable, but it fails to capture the public’s imagination. What does get people excited is the prospect of a mission to Mars. The lure of the red planet lies in its Earth-like conditions and the tantalising prospect of some form of life. Unfortunately, existing plans are absurdly expensive and will remain unrealistic for decades. But there is a way to put humans on Mars with foreseeable technology, and at a fraction of the projected cost. Five years ago I made the radical proposal that a handful of astronauts be sent on a one-way journey to Mars. I am not talking about a suicide mission. With its protective atmosphere, accessible water and carbon dioxide, and significant amounts of methane, Mars is one of the few places in the solar system that could support a human colony. I have presented my idea at NASA conferences, and discussed it with scientists in
other countries. The response has nearly always been positive. There is a persistent myth that nobody would volunteer to go. In fact, I have found no shortage of eager scientists, young and old, who say they would accept a one-way ticket.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[29.- The author´s proposed plan…]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) has run into problems finding volunteers willing to live the rest of their lives on Mars.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) is unlikely to be carried out in the coming decades due to its prohibitive cost.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) has been regarded with suspicion by the scientific community.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) has met with interest despite some misinformation surrounding the idea.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[30.- The author believes that…]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a) NASA has done a good job maintaining public interest in the space program despite
some unexciting missions.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b) NASA needs to have a bold, exciting mission to recapture the public interest.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c) NASA needs to undertake smaller missions with a reduced budget before considering
his Mars plan.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d) NASA should excite the public by returning to the Moon, then set its sights on Mars.]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
</exam>
