<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?><exam id_exam="106R-4" title="Departamento de Idiomas. Escuela de Guerra | INGLÉS" fecha="EXAMEN COMPRENSION TEXTOS ABRIL 2013" tipo="Normal">
<intro1><![CDATA[En las sucesivas presentaciones usted encontrará preguntas de relacionadas con el texto redactado.]]></intro1>
<intro2><![CDATA[Después de leer y comprender el texto presentado deberá responder a una de las preguntas de la parte inferior.]]></intro2>
<intro3><![CDATA[Gracias por su colaboración. A continuación podrá <strong>imprimir</strong> las respuestas que han sido seleccionadas, o bien imprimirlas en un archivo <strong>pdf</strong> para su entrega al profesor correspondiente.]]></intro3>
<tiempoGlobal><![CDATA[75]]></tiempoGlobal>
<timeOver><![CDATA[Su tiempo ha terminado. Pulse finalizar e imprima sus respuestas]]></timeOver>
<user id= "1">LABRADO GOMEZ, CARLOS TIM: 51358887#</user>

<user id= "2">LAGUNA PEREZ, JAVIER TIM: 51652408#</user>

<user id= "3">CAP TOVAR HERNÁNDEZ, GERARDO TIM: 09279594#</user>

<user id= "4">MERINO TORO, LA BEGO TIM: 52104944#</user>

<user id= "5">TCOL. D. ANTONIO PIÑA SANCHEZ TIM: 43012165#</user>

<user id= "6">TCOL. D. ANGEL FERNANDEZ TUR TIM: 45068182#</user>

<user id= "7">T TE. D. ANDRES TORRES CASO TIM: 28800128#</user>

<user id= "8">CAP. ART.  JOSE  FRANCISCO   CAMPOS  BARBERO TIM: 06965997#</user>

<user id= "9">CAP. CAB.  GABRIEL     ECHEVERRIA  URQUIZU TIM: 15992562#</user>

<user id= "10">CAP. ABSTO.  MANUEL  JOSE    CEREZO       LOPEZ TIM: 30499977#</user>

<user id= "11">TCOL. D. GABRIEL AIZPURU DIAZ DE TERAN TIM: 17870902#</user>

<user id= "12">TCOL. JERÓNIMO DELGADO DE LUQUE TIM: 28683622#</user>

<user id= "13">COL. ALFONSO CHILLÓN MODREGO TIM: 17203922#</user>

<question nquest="1">
	<Text><![CDATA[………………………………Andrew Nelson, an 18-year-old schoolboy rescued four people from a helicopter crash. He was playing football at school when he saw the helicopter crash in a nearby field. Immediately Andrew ran a mile to get to the scene of the accident. Andrew, whose father is a flying instructor, knew the helicopter was in danger of exploding but he ran inside and pulled out four adults while the head teacher of his school phoned for an ambulance and the fire brigade.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[1. Which statement is true?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. Andrew Nelson is a flying instructor]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. The helicopter exploded]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. Andrew Nelson saved four people]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. Andrew Nelson called the fire brigade]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="2">
	<Text><![CDATA[President Sarkozy’s Son is Trouble over Tomato Incident.         ………………………………French President Nicolas Sarkozy 15-year-old son has been in trouble for pelting a police officer with tomatoes. The female officer was on duty at the Elysee Palace, guarding the president when she was hit on the cheek. Louis Sarkozy is President Sarkozy’s son from his first marriage. He lives in America but often comes to France to stay with his father. The president apologized to the officer.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[2. What is said about President Sarkozy’s son?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. He was hit by tomatoes]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. The police officer arrested him]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. He apologized to the police officer]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. He was throwing tomatoes]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="3">
	<Text><![CDATA[Travelling by Train.                                      ………………………………Travelling by train has many advantages. There are no stressful traffic jams and trains are fast and comfortable. You can use the time in different ways. You can sit and read or just watch the world go by. You can work or you can have a meal or a snack in the buffet car.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[3. What is said about travelling by trains?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. It is stressful]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. It is efficient]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. It is boring]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. It is time-consuming]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="4">
	<Text><![CDATA[Schoolboy Hero                                   ………………………………Andrew Nelson, an 18-year-old schoolboy rescued four people from a helicopter crash. He was playing football at school when he saw the helicopter crash in a nearby field. Immediately Andrew ran a mile to get to the scene of the accident. Andrew, whose father is a flying instructor, knew the helicopter was in danger of exploding but he ran inside and pulled out four adults while the head teacher of his school phoned for an ambulance and the fire brigade.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[4. Which statement is true?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. Andrew Nelson is a flying instructor]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. The helicopter exploded]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. Andrew Nelson saved four people]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. Andrew Nelson called the fire brigade]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="5">
	<Text><![CDATA[Japanese ‘Ghost Ship’ Drifting Near Canada.                ………………………………A Japanese ‘ghost ship’ has been spotted off the coast of Canada. The fishing boat was swept away by the tsunami in 2011 and has been slowly drifting across the Pacific Ocean. Japanese officials say that there is no-one onboard the vessel. Experts think that it is the first large item of around 25 million tons of debris to cross the ocean as a result of the earthquake and tsunami but most of it isn’t expected to reach North America until 2014.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[5. What is said about the ‘ghost ship’?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. It has come from America]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. It is drifting towards Japan]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. It doesn’t have passengers]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. It avoided the Tsunami]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="6">
	<Text><![CDATA[Slovakian Castle Gets Badly Burned.                           ………………………………The 14th Century Krasna Horka castle has been badly burned, after two young boys set fire to grass while trying to light cigarettes. The boys, aged 11 and 12, caused a blaze that destroyed the castle’s roof and bell tower, as well as ten percent of the historical collections held there. The Krasna Horka has been a National Cultural Monument of the Slovak Republic since 1961.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[6. Which statement is true?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. The castle was completely destroyed]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. The boys intentionally started the fire]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. The castle was partially destroyed]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. The castle used to be a National Monument]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="7">
	<Text><![CDATA[Mexico Hit by 7.6 Magnitude Earthquake.  ………………………………A powerful 7.6 magnitude earthquake struck southwest Mexico yesterday. The 7.6 magnitude earthquake was felt by people several hundred miles away, but didn’t cause any serious damage. The earthquake struck near the tourist resort of Acapulco, just after midday. At first experts thought that it was a 7.9 magnitude earthquake, before downgrading it to 7.6.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[7. What is said about the earthquake?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. It damaged a tourist resort]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. It injured several people]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. It occurred during the night]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. It was felt over a wide area]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="8">
	<Text><![CDATA[Three Rescued After Balloon Gets Trapped in Power Lines.  ………………………………Three people had to be rescued from a hot-air balloon after it got trapped in power cables in Northamptonshire. The canopy of the balloon became tangled in power lines as the pilot was trying to land in a playing field. Firefighters had to wait four hours for the electricity to be made safe before they could begin the rescue. The passengers were stuck 15 meters in the air for almost five hours, but no-one was badly hurt.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[8. Which of the following is true?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. The balloon landed in a playing field]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. The rescue could not begin immediately]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. Several people were injured]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. Firefighter took four hours to arrive]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="9">
	<Text><![CDATA[12-Year-Old Boy Wears a Skirt to School to Protest Against Uniform Rules. J ………………………………A boy is wearing a skirt to school to protest his school uniform’s policy which bans shorts. 12-year-old Chris Whitehead says trousers are too hot and that it’s “discriminatory” that girls can wear skirts in the summer, but boys can’t wear shorts. Chris’s head teacher, Mr. Campbell, said: “The boys can wear a skirt to school because it doesn’t say they can’t in the uniform policy and we would be discriminating against them if we did not allow it.”]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[9. What is said about the uniform policy?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. Girls can wear shorts.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. Boys can’t wear skirts.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. Boys can wear skirts.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. Trousers can’t be worn in summer.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="10">
	<Text><![CDATA[‘Big Cat’ Predator Ruled Out by DNA Tests.  ………………………………Lab tests on two deer found dead in Gloucestershire have ruled out them having been killed by a ‘big cat’. After weeks of testing by scientists, it’s looking more likely they were killed by a fox. Local people aren’t convinced though and believe that big cats are roaming around the Gloucestershire countryside. Rumors of big cats have been around there for some time, with locals describing a ‘panther-like’ animal living in the countryside.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[10. According to the report;]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. The deer were killed by a panther.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. Local residents disbelieve the test results.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. Local residents trust the test results.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. The rumors of big cats are true.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="11">
	<Text><![CDATA[‘Les Miserables’ Role Surprise For U.K. Actress.  ………………………………It could have been a scene in a Hollywood movie. The moment an unknown actress from the Isle of Man was told she was going to be a star in an upcoming blockbuster movie! That’s just what happened to Samantha Barks, when a top producer told her after a stage performance. She’ll now play Eponine, in a film version of the musical ‘Les Miserables’ alongside Hollywood screen stars. It was a total surprise for the actress, who’d just finished performing in ‘Oliver’ at Manchester’s Palace Theater.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[11. What is said about Samantha Barks?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. She was discovered in Hollywood.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. She was famous in the U.K.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. She wasn’t expecting the film role.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. She had auditioned for the film role.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="12">
	<Text><![CDATA[Teenage Girl Breaks Sailing Record.  ………………………………Dutch 16-year-old, Laura Dekker, has become the youngest solo sailor ever to sail around the world. But Laura won’t be sailing into the record books. Dutch officials took legal action to try to stop Laura when she announced she was going to try to break the record in a small boat. Guinness World Records decided to stop recognizing records for youngest sailors because of the danger. But Laura won a 10-month court battle to make the journey after saying she would buy a bigger boat and learn first aid.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[12. What is said about Guinness World Records?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. Laura received its support.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. It is worried about risks to young sailors.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. It stopped Laura from making the voyage.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. Laura will appear in its next edition.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="13">
	<Text><![CDATA[‘Hugo’ and ‘The Artist’ Lead This Year’s Oscar Nominations.  ………………………………This year’s Oscar nominations have been announced and it looks like Uggie, the dog, will need his bow tie again! This silent black and white movie ‘The Artist’ is up for 10 awards. It is also up for the top prize of Best Picture,  alongside 3D action adventure ‘Hugo’ and Steven Spielberg’s ‘War Horse’. ‘Hugo’, which is set in 1930’s Paris, got the most nominations overall, with a total of 11. The red carpet will be rolled out once again to welcome the movie stars to the Kodak Theatre in Hollywood.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[13. Which of the following is true?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. ‘Hugo’ won 11 awards.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. ‘The Artist’ won 10 awards.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. ‘War Horse’ could win best film.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. The nominees will be broadcast soon.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="14">
	<Text><![CDATA[Golden Cape and Scarf Made of a Million Spider’s Silk.  ………………………………Spider-Man is known for spinning webs and swinging from building to building but maybe he should have thought of becoming a fashion designer! Later this month, the only large textiles in the world created from the silk of spiders goes on display. An embroidered cape and a 4-meter long scarf have both been spun for the silk of more than a million spiders. The clothes have taken seven years to create and they are a golden color. The cape and the scarf came from Golden Orb Weaver spiders collected in the highlands of Madagascar.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[14. What is said about the clothes?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. They are part of a line made from spiders’ silk.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. They were made in Madagascar.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. A famous fashion designer made them from silk.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. The material used to create them came from spiders.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="15">
	<Text><![CDATA[Sierra Leone: All Boom But No Progress?  ………………………………In the center of Sierra Leone, in a majestic green valley, a new hydro-electric dam symbolizes both progress and frustration. Ten years after the end of the civil war here, a construction boom is under way. The Bumbuna dam is one of the biggest recent projects. But the economy is so run down by decades of war and corruption that it will take many more years, if at all before the boom benefits most of the population. But now, electricity is being produced. There are many other projects under way. A stone crushing plant just outside the capital, Freetown, spews clouds of smoke and dust into the surrounding mountains. Major roads are being built in Freetown and between regional towns. Two big ore mining projects have recently begun. But the permanent jobs created by these projects number just a few tens of thousands; the population of Sierra Leone is six million.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[15. What is said about Sierra Leone?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. All the population benefits from the developments]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. The developments have provided millions of jobs]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. The construction of the dam is on hold]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. There are several new projects in progress]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="16">
	<Text><![CDATA[Male Dolphins Live in ‘Gangs’ to Protect Females.             ………………………………We already knew that dolphins are clever creatures but it turns out that they are even more like humans than we thought. Scientists studying bottlenose dolphins in Australia have discovered that the males live in gangs. By travelling in groups, the males have better chances of protecting their females and fighting off rival gangs. Until now, only humans and elephants were known to live in complex social groups. The study found that male dolphins can belong to around three separate groups, all of different sizes. When a gang encounters a group of males, they then decide if the new dolphins will be friends or enemies. Occasionally, the males even switch groups and join a different gang they meet on their travels.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[16. What is said about male dolphins?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. They live in gangs to protect themselves]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. The can sometimes change gangs]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. They gangs are always hostile to each other]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. A male dolphin always stays in the same gang]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="17">
	<Text><![CDATA[Abandoned and Stray Dogs Have Risen For the 11th Year.  ………………………………There’s an old saying that we hear every year; ‘a dog is for life, and not just for Christmas.’ But it seems people still aren’t getting the message. Many people find the gift of a four-legged friend is a lot of hard work and they don’t find it easy coping with a new addition to the family and go on to abandon their pets. Figures from the recent Stray Dogs Survey, show for the 11th year in a row the number of stray and abandoned dogs in Britain has risen. Last year around 126,000 stray dogs were picked up across the UK- that’s more than 300 a day.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[17. The report states;]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. Many people receive dogs as Christmas presents.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. The number of abandoned dogs is decreasing.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. Dogs received as a Christmas gift are less likely to be abandoned.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. There are currently more abandoned dogs than ever before.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="18">
	<Text><![CDATA[Mars Mission Gets Back on Track.  ………………………………The Mars Science Laboratory (MSL), currently flying through space, has had its route corrected so it will land on the planet Mars in August. It was launched in November on a rocket from America, but it wasn’t travelling in exactly the right direction. In a three-hour process, it was put on course by firing up eight thrusters. The total journey from Earth is a staggering 570 million kilometers. It will have to be corrected again before it can land, but scientists say this is normal for a space flight to Mars.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[18. What is said about the Mars Science Lab (MSL)?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. It will reach its destination in November.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. Its route will need further adjustment.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. Scientists were surprised its route needed correction.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. Scientists do not expect it to reach its destination.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="19">
	<Text><![CDATA[Farmers Must Take Care of Countryside.  ………………………………Farmers should take better care of our countryside, according to a poll by the Campaign to Protect Rural England. (CPRE). The CPRE is calling for changes, as farming can be hard on the environment. For example, lots of animals like dormice are decreasing in numbers because their habitat is being used to grow crops. Farmers can help the environment by digging ponds, keeping more livestock and growing a greater range of fruit and vegetables.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[19. The report states that;]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. Farmers don’t want to change their methods.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. The number of dormice is rising.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. Farmers shouldn’t keep so much livestock.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. Farmers should cultivate more vegetables.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="20">
	<Text><![CDATA[Henry the Eighth Have a Secret Daughter?  ………………………………According to historian Elizabeth Norton, who has been examining royal records, Elizabeth Tailboys was the child of King Henry the Eighth and his mistress, Bessie Blount. Elizabeth was adopted by her stepfather, Gilbert Tailboys. But, if the King had claimed her as his, she would have become queen, as she was older than his daughter with Anne Boleyn, who was also called Elizabeth and went on to become Queen Elizabeth 1.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[20. What is said about King Henry the Eighth?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. He didn’t claim his older daughter.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. He didn’t want a second daughter.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. His older daughter inherited the throne.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. His older daughter was recognized as his.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="21">
	<Text><![CDATA[Open or Closed Society is Key Dividing Line of 21st Century.  ………………………………Nations will be divided not between east and west, or along religious lines, but between open and closed societies, the U.S. secretary of state, Hilary Clinton has said. Countries that are closed to “change, ideas, cultures and beliefs that are different from theirs will quickly find that in an internet world they will be left behind,” Clinton said. “In the 21st century, the U.S. is convinced that one of the most significant divisions between nations will be not between east or west, nor over religion, so much as between open and closed societies,” she said. “We believe those governments that hide from public view and dismiss ideas of openness and the aspirations of their people for greater freedom will find it increasingly difficult to create a secure society.”]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[21. What did Hilary Clinton say at the Brasilia conference?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. Countries will be divided by culture]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. Countries need to be open to differences]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. Many countries need to change their lifestyle]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. Governments are increasingly rejecting openness]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="22">
	<Text><![CDATA[The Man Who Helped Simplify Chinese.  ………………………………His older daughter inherited the throne.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[22. What is said about Zhou Youguang?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. He used to be a literacy teacher in China]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. He is a renowned figure in China]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. He disapproves of the Chinese government]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. He boasts about his work]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="23">
	<Text><![CDATA[Liberians Hope Long Wait for the Web is Finally Over.  ………………………………Getting online is difficult in Liberia. Connections are slow and expensive. A crowd gathers on a sandy beach near central Monrovia to watch as a diver emerges from the sea. He’s pulling a rope which a team on the beach helps drag ashore. Eventually a black fiber-optic cable pops out of the water and slithers up the sand, prompting cheers from the crowd. The cable will eventually provide broadband connectivity to more than 20 countries. News of the cable’s arrival on land is welcomed by a small group of men in an internet café in Monrovia. For them, getting online currently costs around $2 per hour –more money than many Liberians earn in a day. The current high cost and relatively slow internet connection in Liberia is not surprising, says Calestous Juma, an expert in telecommunications in Africa. “Fiber optic cables have more capacity and provide more consistent data flow than the current satellite connections being used.”]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[23. Which of the following is true?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. Fiber optic cables are now in use in Liberia.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. Liberians now have access to broadband.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. For most Liberians, internet use is relatively cheap.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. The fiber optic cable could revolutionize internet use in Liberia.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="24">
	<Text><![CDATA[More Landmines are Being Laid Worldwide, Research Shows.  ………………………………Research has found that more and more landmines are being laid around the world. Landmines are used in war-torn countries all over the world and around 10,000 children are killed or seriously injured by them every year. Even though 80% of countries have signed up to a treaty to ban the use of landmines, countries like Syria, Libya and Israel are still planting the devices. Over the years many campaigns have tried to get them banned. Diana, Princess of Wales famously called for an international ban on landmines in 1997. Celebrities have also backed campaigns. Hollywood star Angelina Jolie saw the damage landmines can cause when she was filming the Tomb Raider movie in Cambodia. But despite worldwide campaigns, more mines were laid last year than in any year since 2004.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[24. The report states that;]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. Campaigns to ban landmines are proving effective.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. More than half the world’s nations have pledged not to use landmines.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. The majority of countries are reluctant to sign a treaty against landmines.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. Angelina Jolie organized an anti-landmine campaign in Cambodia.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="25">
	<Text><![CDATA[As Asia Booms, What is Cost of Success for its Young?  ………………………………On a Saturday night in Singapore, Nicol and his friends are dancing in a dark and crowded room at one of the most expensive new clubs in the city. For Nicol and others like him partying across the city and the region, it would seem that there has never been a better time to be young and in Asia. Instead of the economic problems and social issues that faced their parents’ and grandparents’ generations, Asia’s youth today have a chance to access a period of unprecedented prosperity and expansion. “There are only some pockets of growth left in the world and Asia happens to be one of them,” Nicol explains. “There’s opportunity and optimism out here.” For hundreds of millions of people across the region, their earning power and standard of living are increasing. The youth unemployment rate has been below 15% in most the region for the last five years. Compare that with figures of more than 30% in European economies. This focus on youth employment is important because Asia is the region with the most young people in the world.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[25. According to the report;]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. Asia’s economic boom began in previous generations.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. The Asian youth unemployment rate exceeds that of Europe.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. Asians have a positive outlook for the future.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. Young Asians yearn for the life their parents and grandparents had.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="26">
	<Text><![CDATA[Birds Perform Amazing Aerial Display.  ………………………………Thousands of birds in Wales are performing amazing aerial displays at dusk. It’s believed 100,000 starlings have arrived at Llanelli Nature Reserve to prepare for the winter. The birds’ spectacular displays include swirling and swooping –experts believe the birds do this to avoid being eaten by predators. Some of the starlings are from the UK but most have come from Russia and Scandinavia.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[26. What is said about the starling birds?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. They fly during the early evening.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. The majority are from the U.K.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. Many have been eaten by predators.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. They will leave the reserve in winter.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="27">
	<Text><![CDATA[Should School Day be Longer.  ………………………………The school day should be longer to get children ready for the world of work, say some politicians. Stephen Twigg, the Labor Party’s education boss, says a longer day would keep children off the streets, stop them being sucked into local gangs and give the most deprived pupils a place to study away from difficult home lives. He also thinks that pupils should be put into groups in schools by ability or interests, rather than age. The MP’s comments come after a survey by business leaders found that one out of three young people was not ready for a job.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[27. What is said about a longer school day?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. It could encourage children to join gangs.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. It could facilitate the development of studious habits.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. Business leaders generally disapprove of it.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. It could encourage enthusiasm for life in the work force.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="28">
	<Text><![CDATA[Elephant and Bee Researcher Nets Green Prize.  ………………………………A British scientist has won a coveted environment research prize for showing how bees can be used to reduce conflict between people and elephants. Lucy King’s work proved that beehive ‘fences’ can keep elephants out of African farmers’ fields or compounds. The animals are scared of bees, which can sting them inside their trunks, and flee when they hear buzzing. Dr. King received the prize at the Convention on Migratory Species meeting in Norway. The African -born scientist, whose research was supervised at Oxford University, said she was delighted and surprised to receive the prize. Working in Kenya, she and her team showed that more than 90% of elephants will flee when they hear the sounds of buzzing bees. They used the findings to construct barriers where beehives are woven into a fence, keeping the elephants away from places where people live and grow food.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[28. The report states that;]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. Dr. King’s discovery will be used to protect food sources.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. Dr. King was awarded the prize in Oxford.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. Dr. King developed her theory while working at Oxford University.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. Elephants appear to be attracted to the sound of buzzing bees.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="29">
	<Text><![CDATA[Banksy’s Painting Go On Sale.  ………………………………Paintings by famous graffiti artist Banksy are going on sale at an exclusive auction house in London. Seventeen works of art by Banksy are being auctioned at the Bonhams Urban Art Sale. This is a big step for Banksy because it shows that people in the art world consider him a real artist. Some people looked down on him previously because he was a graffiti artist. The artwork being sold includes a screen print of British supermodel Kate Moss, inspired by Andy Warhol’s Marilyn Monroe picture. Banksy has lots of famous fans including Kate Moss and Harry Potter actress, Helena Bonham Carter.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[29. What is said about Banksy?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. The art world has always respected him]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. He painted a famous portrait of Marilyn Monroe]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. His works will be sold at an important venue]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. His works are not expected to attract much attention]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="30">
	<Text><![CDATA[Tamara Rojo to be Artistic Director of English National Ballet.  ………………………………Tamara Rojo, prima ballerina at the Royal Ballet, is to become artistic director of English National Ballet. The 37-year-old dancer will take over in September from Wayne Eagling, whose unexpected departure after seven years was recently announced. Rojo, a principal dancer at the Royal Ballet, said she was honored to be taking over at a company she spent three years with in the late 1990s. Rojo takes over in difficult economic times. The English National Ballet, which tours extensively nationally and internationally, has been hit by a 15% but in Arts Council funding. Rojo spent three years with the company after she left Spain in 1996, making a significant splash for performances which prompted the ‘Times’ to call her ‘dance revelation of the year’. After that, she joined the Royal Ballet where her reputation has gone from strength to strength.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[30. What is said about Tamara Rojo?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. She will be the artistic director of the Royal Ballet]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. She previously danced with the English National Ballet]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. She dance with the Royal Ballet for seven years]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. Funding will increase when she takes over the ballet company]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
</exam>
