<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?><exam id_exam="106" title="Departamento de Idiomas. Escuela de Guerra | INGLÉS" fecha="01/04/2013" tipo="Normal">
<intro1><![CDATA[En las sucesivas presentaciones usted encontrará preguntas de relacionadas con el texto redactado.]]></intro1>
<intro2><![CDATA[Después de leer y comprender el texto presentado deberá responder a una de las preguntas de la parte inferior.]]></intro2>
<intro3><![CDATA[Gracias por su colaboración. A continuación podrá <strong>imprimir</strong> las respuestas que han sido seleccionadas, o bien imprimirlas en un archivo <strong>pdf</strong> para su entrega al profesor correspondiente.]]></intro3>
<tiempoGlobal><![CDATA[75]]></tiempoGlobal>
<timeOver><![CDATA[Su tiempo ha terminado. Pulse finalizar e imprima sus respuestas]]></timeOver>
<user id= "1">LABRADO GOMEZ, CARLOS TIM: 51358887#</user>

<user id= "2">LAGUNA PEREZ, JAVIER TIM: 51652408#</user>

<user id= "3">CAP TOVAR HERNÁNDEZ, GERARDO TIM: 09279594#</user>

<user id= "4">MERINO TORO, LA BEGO TIM: 52104944#</user>

<user id= "5">TCOL. D. ANTONIO PIÑA SANCHEZ TIM: 43012165#</user>

<user id= "6">TCOL. D. ANGEL FERNANDEZ TUR TIM: 45068182#</user>

<user id= "7">T TE. D. ANDRES TORRES CASO TIM: 28800128#</user>

<user id= "8">CAP. ART.  JOSE  FRANCISCO   CAMPOS  BARBERO TIM: 06965997#</user>

<user id= "9">CAP. CAB.  GABRIEL     ECHEVERRIA  URQUIZU TIM: 15992562#</user>

<user id= "10">CAP. ABSTO.  MANUEL  JOSE    CEREZO       LOPEZ TIM: 30499977#</user>

<user id= "11">TCOL. D. GABRIEL AIZPURU DIAZ DE TERAN TIM: 17870902#</user>

<user id= "12">TCOL. JERÓNIMO DELGADO DE LUQUE TIM: 28683622#</user>

<user id= "13">COL. ALFONSO CHILLÓN MODREGO TIM: 17203922#</user>

<question nquest="1">
	<Text><![CDATA[President Sarkozy’s Son is Trouble over Tomato Incident.         ………………………………French President Nicolas Sarkozy 15-year-old son has been in trouble for pelting a police officer with tomatoes. The female officer was on duty at the Elysee Palace, guarding the president when she was hit on the cheek. Louis Sarkozy is President Sarkozy’s son from his first marriage. He lives in America but often comes to France to stay with his father. The president apologized to the officer.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[1. What is said about President Sarkozy’s son?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. He was hit by tomatoes]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. The police officer arrested him]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. He apologized to the police officer]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. He was throwing tomatoes]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="2">
	<Text><![CDATA[Hero Saves Man’s Life.                                                       ………………………………Jack Easton was driving home from work at 6.30 in the evening when he saw a yellow van, driven by James Smith, crash into a tree. Without thinking of his own safety, he pulled the young man out of the van and took him to hospital. James is making good progress.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[2. Which statement is true?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. Jack Easton crashed his car]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. James Smith will not recover]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. Jack Easton assisted James Smith]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. Jack Easton worried about his safety]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="3">
	<Text><![CDATA[Schoolboy Hero                                   ………………………………Andrew Nelson, an 18-year-old schoolboy rescued four people from a helicopter crash. He was playing football at school when he saw the helicopter crash in a nearby field. Immediately Andrew ran a mile to get to the scene of the accident. Andrew, whose father is a flying instructor, knew the helicopter was in danger of exploding but he ran inside and pulled out four adults while the head teacher of his school phoned for an ambulance and the fire brigade.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[3. Which statement is true?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. Andrew Nelson is a flying instructor]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. The helicopter exploded]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. Andrew Nelson saved four people]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. Andrew Nelson called the fire brigade]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="4">
	<Text><![CDATA[Should Supermarket Carrier Bags be Banned?  ………………………………New European rules are being brought in to reduce the number of plastic carrier bags we use. In 2011, Italy became the first country in Europe to prohibit the bags but in 2010 the number of bags in the U.K. went up after four years of going down. More than six billion bags were used and campaigners want to reduce this number. Discarded bags in the sea cause some parts of the ocean to be like ‘plastic soup’, say politicians. Some countries have banned thin plastic bags, including China and South Africa.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[4. What is said about plastic carrier bags?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. Their use is declining in England]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. Their use is widespread in China]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. They are no longer used in Italy]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. They can be dissolved by the sea]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="5">
	<Text><![CDATA[Slovakian Castle Gets Badly Burned.                           ………………………………The 14th Century Krasna Horka castle has been badly burned, after two young boys set fire to grass while trying to light cigarettes. The boys, aged 11 and 12, caused a blaze that destroyed the castle’s roof and bell tower, as well as ten percent of the historical collections held there. The Krasna Horka has been a National Cultural Monument of the Slovak Republic since 1961.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[5. Which statement is true?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. The castle was completely destroyed]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. The boys intentionally started the fire]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. The castle was partially destroyed]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. The castle used to be a National Monument]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="6">
	<Text><![CDATA[Seven Rescued After Cargo Ship Crashes in Wales.  ……………………………… A Royal Navy sea king helicopter and two lifeboats rescued seven crew members after a cargo ship ran aground in Wales. The ship crashed into rocks during a storm which saw gale force winds and five-meter tall waves battering it. Assistant Chief Constable Gareth Pritchard said: “This was a very difficult operation involving many agencies in very bad weather. Everyone is delighted that the seven crewmen were rescued without injury and they are safe and well. The Welsh Government is closely monitoring the ship to make sure that fuel doesn’t leak into the sea.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[6. Which statement is true?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a.  The rescue operation failed]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. Bad weather affected the ship]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. Fuel has spilt from the ship]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. One agency attempted the rescue]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="7">
	<Text><![CDATA[Three Rescued After Balloon Gets Trapped in Power Lines.  ………………………………Three people had to be rescued from a hot-air balloon after it got trapped in power cables in Northamptonshire. The canopy of the balloon became tangled in power lines as the pilot was trying to land in a playing field. Firefighters had to wait four hours for the electricity to be made safe before they could begin the rescue. The passengers were stuck 15 meters in the air for almost five hours, but no-one was badly hurt.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[7. Which of the following is true?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. The balloon landed in a playing field]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. The rescue could not begin immediately]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. Several people were injured]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. Firefighter took four hours to arrive]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="8">
	<Text><![CDATA[Scientists Have Created Toxic Glow Fish.                                ………………………………Fish that glow green when put in polluted water have been created in a British lab. It is hoped the luminous zebra fish will help improve the cleanliness of our rivers and help identify dangerous chemicals that get in to our water supply. The fish are designed so that the parts of their bodies harmed by pollutants light up. The advance was made at Exeter University. Chemicals from paints and many plastics often find their way in to our rivers, causing many creatures to have problems breeding as well as causing harm to humans. Professor Charles Tyler, who led the study, said: “This zebrafish gives us a better view than ever before of the potential effects of these chemicals on the body. It is very exciting.”]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[8. What is said about the toxic glow fish?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. They are not affected by pollutants in the water]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. They will indicate the presence of chemicals]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. They glow green when the water is safe]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. They usually have problems breeding]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="9">
	<Text><![CDATA[‘Yes Scotland’ Independence Campaign Kicks Off.  ………………………………The offical campaign to persuade people in Scotland to vote for independence is kicking off. A big vote, expected in 2014, will ask Scots whether they want Scotland to separate from the U.K. and become its own country. The ‘Yes Scotland’ campaign is being led by the Scottish National Party and the launch is set to include Scots from many different backgrounds. An opposing campaign to keep Scotland a part of the UK will also begin soon. Scotland has its own parliament at the moment and it has power over many things such as education, police and transport. But some things such as national security and foreign policy are decided by UK politicians in Westminster. Scotland has been united with England since 1707.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[9. Which statement is true?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. The campaign has little support]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. Scottish education is controlled by the UK]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. Some Scots want to remain part of the UK]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. The Scottish National Party opposes the campaign]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="10">
	<Text><![CDATA[‘Big Cat’ Predator Ruled Out by DNA Tests.  ………………………………Lab tests on two deer found dead in Gloucestershire have ruled out them having been killed by a ‘big cat’. After weeks of testing by scientists, it’s looking more likely they were killed by a fox. Local people aren’t convinced though and believe that big cats are roaming around the Gloucestershire countryside. Rumors of big cats have been around there for some time, with locals describing a ‘panther-like’ animal living in the countryside.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[10. According to the report;]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. The deer were killed by a panther.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. Local residents disbelieve the test results.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. Local residents trust the test results.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. The rumors of big cats are true.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="11">
	<Text><![CDATA[Teenage Girl Breaks Sailing Record.  ………………………………Dutch 16-year-old, Laura Dekker, has become the youngest solo sailor ever to sail around the world. But Laura won’t be sailing into the record books. Dutch officials took legal action to try to stop Laura when she announced she was going to try to break the record in a small boat. Guinness World Records decided to stop recognizing records for youngest sailors because of the danger. But Laura won a 10-month court battle to make the journey after saying she would buy a bigger boat and learn first aid.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[11. What is said about Guinness World Records?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. Laura received its support.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. It is worried about risks to young sailors.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. It stopped Laura from making the voyage.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. Laura will appear in its next edition.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="12">
	<Text><![CDATA[Rowing adventure………………………………Six rowers who were crossing the Atlantic Ocean have been rescued after their boat tipped over. The men, five from Britain and one from Ireland, were trying to break a record by rowing from Morocco to Barbados in under 30 days. The crew was 27 days into their adventure when they got into trouble. They were picked up by a ship and are expected to reach land by February 9.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[12. What could be said about the rowers?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. They were all English.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. They broke a record.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. Their boat turned over.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. They had problems for 27 days.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="13">
	<Text><![CDATA[Golden Cape and Scarf Made of a Million Spider’s Silk.  ………………………………Spider-Man is known for spinning webs and swinging from building to building but maybe he should have thought of becoming a fashion designer! Later this month, the only large textiles in the world created from the silk of spiders goes on display. An embroidered cape and a 4-meter long scarf have both been spun for the silk of more than a million spiders. The clothes have taken seven years to create and they are a golden color. The cape and the scarf came from Golden Orb Weaver spiders collected in the highlands of Madagascar.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[13. What is said about the clothes?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. They are part of a line made from spiders’ silk.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. They were made in Madagascar.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. A famous fashion designer made them from silk.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. The material used to create them came from spiders.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="14">
	<Text><![CDATA[Great Barrier Reef Examined Over Fears of Mining Damage.  ………………………………A United Nations team are in Australia to investigate possible damage to the Great Barrier Reef by mining. Home to 400 types of coral and 1,500 species of fish, the Reef lies off the coast of Queensland, Australia’s biggest coal producer. Environmentalists are worried that coal mining and gas exploration are threatening the reef’s future. They say the plans to increase coal production will mean more big ships carrying coal will damage the reef. John Hepburn from Greenpeace called it, “a reckless expansion that will have direct impact.” The UN team will spend a week examining the reef for any signs of pollution or damage.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[14. What is said about Great Barrier Reef?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. It is obstructing gas exploration]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. There is apprehension it will suffer damage]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. Coal mining is prohibited in its vicinity]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. The UN found it to be extensively damaged]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="15">
	<Text><![CDATA[Male Dolphins Live in ‘Gangs’ to Protect Females.             ………………………………We already knew that dolphins are clever creatures but it turns out that they are even more like humans than we thought. Scientists studying bottlenose dolphins in Australia have discovered that the males live in gangs. By travelling in groups, the males have better chances of protecting their females and fighting off rival gangs. Until now, only humans and elephants were known to live in complex social groups. The study found that male dolphins can belong to around three separate groups, all of different sizes. When a gang encounters a group of males, they then decide if the new dolphins will be friends or enemies. Occasionally, the males even switch groups and join a different gang they meet on their travels.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[15. What is said about male dolphins?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. They live in gangs to protect themselves]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. The can sometimes change gangs]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. They gangs are always hostile to each other]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. A male dolphin always stays in the same gang]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="16">
	<Text><![CDATA[Pakistan’s Sports Minister Wants to Share His Stamp Collection with World.  ………………………………Pakistan’s sports minister, Mohammed Ali Shah wants to change people’s perception of Pakistan-by turning it into the stamp collecting capital of the world! He said that he wants to promote a softer image of his violence-wracked country through his stamp collection. Mr. Shah has collected more than 10,000 stamps from all over the world, including a very rare ‘Penny Black’, the first sticky-backed postage stamp issued by Britain in 1840. “It is said that philately (stamp collecting) is the king of all hobbies and the hobby of kings,” said Mr. Shah.  Queen Elizabeth of England, too, is known to be a big collector of stamps. But due to email and the decrease in sending mail by post, one post office is closed down in England every month.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[16. What is said about Pakistan?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. Stamp collecting is very popular in Pakistan]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. Mr. Shah hopes to alter peoples’ views of Pakistan]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. Most of stamps collected in Pakistan come from Britain]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. Many post offices are now closing in Pakistan]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="17">
	<Text><![CDATA[Mars Mission Gets Back on Track.  ………………………………The Mars Science Laboratory (MSL), currently flying through space, has had its route corrected so it will land on the planet Mars in August. It was launched in November on a rocket from America, but it wasn’t travelling in exactly the right direction. In a three-hour process, it was put on course by firing up eight thrusters. The total journey from Earth is a staggering 570 million kilometers. It will have to be corrected again before it can land, but scientists say this is normal for a space flight to Mars.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[17. What is said about the Mars Science Lab (MSL)?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. It will reach its destination in November.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. Its route will need further adjustment.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. Scientists were surprised its route needed correction.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. Scientists do not expect it to reach its destination.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="18">
	<Text><![CDATA[Henry the Eighth Have a Secret Daughter?  ………………………………According to historian Elizabeth Norton, who has been examining royal records, Elizabeth Tailboys was the child of King Henry the Eighth and his mistress, Bessie Blount. Elizabeth was adopted by her stepfather, Gilbert Tailboys. But, if the King had claimed her as his, she would have become queen, as she was older than his daughter with Anne Boleyn, who was also called Elizabeth and went on to become Queen Elizabeth 1.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[18. What is said about King Henry the Eighth?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. He didn’t claim his older daughter.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. He didn’t want a second daughter.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. His older daughter inherited the throne.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. His older daughter was recognized as his.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="19">
	<Text><![CDATA[Michael Jackson Honored in Hollywood.  ………………………………Michael Jackson has become the first celebrity to have his hand and footprints put on the Hollywood Walk of Fame after his death. Thousands of fans watched his children, Paris, Prince Michael and Blanket, use his famous sequined glove and shoes to make the impressions. Loads of celebrities including Justin Bieber were also at the ceremony. The imprints will be placed alongside other Hollywood screen legends for fans to see.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[19. Which of the following is true?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. Michael Jackson’s children watched a ceremony in his honor.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. Other celebrities were honored in the same ceremony.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. Michael Jackson’s accessories were used in the ceremony.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. Michael Jackson’s fans can make imprints close to his.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="20">
	<Text><![CDATA[Wildlife Film-Maker John Varty Mauled by Tiger.          ………………………………A wildlife documentary-maker is seriously injured after being mauled by a tiger in South Africa. John Varty, 61, who is pioneering a controversial project to create a free-ranging, self-sustaining tiger population outside Asia, was attacked on his Tiger Canyons farm and taken to hospital, where he underwent six-hour emergency surgery. Varty suffered multiple injuries and puncture wounds all over his body and required a blood transfusion. Amanda Appelgryn, spokeswoman for the hospital, said Varty was conscious and she had spoken to him but he is not yet out of danger. She said: “He has multiple injuries all over his whole body but not his face. He’s not stable and he’s not critical, but somewhere in between. It’s best to say he’s in a serious condition. I can’t say he’s out of danger: with wild animals, there’s always the possibility of infection.”]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[20. What is said about John Varty and the tiger attack?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. His face was badly damaged]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. He is making a good recovery]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. He is unable to communicate]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. His condition could go either way]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="21">
	<Text><![CDATA[The Man Who Helped Simplify Chinese.  ………………………………Students struggling to learn Chinese might not know it, but their task has been made easier because of the work of one man. Zhou Youguang helped invent Pinyin, a writing system that turns Chinese characters into words using letters from the Roman alphabet. This is credited with helping raise literacy rates in China. Despite his achievements, Mr. Zhou remains largely unknown in his home country. Perhaps that is because the 106-year-old is a defiant character, refusing to take much credit for his work or pander to the Chinese Communist Party.  He is critical of the party that governs China and old enough not to care who is listening to what he has to say. Mr. Zhou’s life has coincided with most of the momentous events of China’s recent history, as it has moved from imperial dynasty to peoples’ republic to capitalist powerhouse.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[21. What is said about Zhou Youguang?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. He used to be a literacy teacher in China]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. He is a renowned figure in China]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. He disapproves of the Chinese government]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. He boasts about his work]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="22">
	<Text><![CDATA[Is English or Mandarin the Language of the Future?            ………………………………He is unable to communicate]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[22. Which statement is true?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. Classes are given in English in Malaysian schools]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. Malaysian graduates are sought after in the I.T. industry]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. The standard of English has declined in Malaysia]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. Students from Singapore attend classes in Malaysia]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="23">
	<Text><![CDATA[More Landmines are Being Laid Worldwide, Research Shows.  ………………………………Research has found that more and more landmines are being laid around the world. Landmines are used in war-torn countries all over the world and around 10,000 children are killed or seriously injured by them every year. Even though 80% of countries have signed up to a treaty to ban the use of landmines, countries like Syria, Libya and Israel are still planting the devices. Over the years many campaigns have tried to get them banned. Diana, Princess of Wales famously called for an international ban on landmines in 1997. Celebrities have also backed campaigns. Hollywood star Angelina Jolie saw the damage landmines can cause when she was filming the Tomb Raider movie in Cambodia. But despite worldwide campaigns, more mines were laid last year than in any year since 2004.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[23. The report states that;]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. Campaigns to ban landmines are proving effective.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. More than half the world’s nations have pledged not to use landmines.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. The majority of countries are reluctant to sign a treaty against landmines.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. Angelina Jolie organized an anti-landmine campaign in Cambodia.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="24">
	<Text><![CDATA[Pierre Cardin Feud Tears Village Apart.   ………………………………Fashion designer Pierre Cardin has upset the locals in the French village of Lacoste, by buying the Marquis de Sade’s famous castle and 22 more properties.  Lacoste was once the home of the champion debauchee, the Marquis de Sade .Steep cobbled streets and ancient houses lend an archetypal beauty. This part of the Luberon has always drawn eminent outsiders. But it is the fashion designer, Pierre Cardin, who has left by far the deepest imprint on Lacoste. Indeed for many locals, the Cardin mark is too deep. They wish he would go away. Some say he has destroyed the community by spraying his money and driving up prices. For others, he is a generous philanthropist who provides much-needed local employment. Cardin’s own story is a long march from humble beginnings to fame and enormous wealth. But he has always been regarded as something of an upstart by the fashion elite – no doubt because of his working-class origins.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[24. Which of the following is true?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. Pierre Cardin is viewed by some as a benefactor.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. Pierre Cardin is highly respected by the fashion elite.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. The Lacoste locals are starting to leave their village.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d.  Prices in Lacoste have decreased with the arrival of Cardin.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="25">
	<Text><![CDATA[Birds Perform Amazing Aerial Display.  ………………………………Thousands of birds in Wales are performing amazing aerial displays at dusk. It’s believed 100,000 starlings have arrived at Llanelli Nature Reserve to prepare for the winter. The birds’ spectacular displays include swirling and swooping –experts believe the birds do this to avoid being eaten by predators. Some of the starlings are from the UK but most have come from Russia and Scandinavia.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[25. What is said about the starling birds?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. They fly during the early evening.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. The majority are from the U.K.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. Many have been eaten by predators.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. They will leave the reserve in winter.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="26">
	<Text><![CDATA[Seal Pups on the Mend After Being Battered by Storms.  ………………………………The big storms a few weeks ago caused loads of problems across the country – trees were blown down, power lines were cut and roofs were torn off houses. But it wasn’t just humans that had a hard time: seal pups were caught up in the bad weather too. The RSPCA has said it’s seen a big increase in sick seals recently. The storms made it really hard for some of the grey seals to find their way to food and the choppy water meant lots of them were stranded on rocks.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[26. What is said about the seal pups?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. They caused a lot of problems.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. They were stranded in rough water.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. They had difficulty obtaining food.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. They were unaffected by the storm.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="27">
	<Text><![CDATA[Elephant and Bee Researcher Nets Green Prize.  ………………………………A British scientist has won a coveted environment research prize for showing how bees can be used to reduce conflict between people and elephants. Lucy King’s work proved that beehive ‘fences’ can keep elephants out of African farmers’ fields or compounds. The animals are scared of bees, which can sting them inside their trunks, and flee when they hear buzzing. Dr. King received the prize at the Convention on Migratory Species meeting in Norway. The African -born scientist, whose research was supervised at Oxford University, said she was delighted and surprised to receive the prize. Working in Kenya, she and her team showed that more than 90% of elephants will flee when they hear the sounds of buzzing bees. They used the findings to construct barriers where beehives are woven into a fence, keeping the elephants away from places where people live and grow food.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[27. The report states that;]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. Dr. King’s discovery will be used to protect food sources.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. Dr. King was awarded the prize in Oxford.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. Dr. King developed her theory while working at Oxford University.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. Elephants appear to be attracted to the sound of buzzing bees.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="28">
	<Text><![CDATA[Eroding Taboos See Lemurs End Up on Dinner Tables.  ………………………………The erosion of traditional cultural taboos in Madagascar has led to an unsustainable number of lemurs being killed for bush meat. Locals revered these primates, believing that the animals were family ancestors, but the influx of outside influences has seen a breakdown in these views. Some species do not reach maturity for up to nine years and produce offspring once every two or three years. A survey of locals’ eating habits showed that hunting of protected species in eastern Madagascar was increasing. It suggested the rise in illegal hunting was the result of rapid social change, an increase in demand for meat and a decline in traditional taboos. “When you have globalization and outside influences, traditional cultures break down and change faster,” explained co-author Julia Jones from Bangor University. “What seems to be happening in some of the remote areas around the nation’s eastern rainforests is that a lot of legal gold mining is springing up, so people from outside are moving into the area.”]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[28. What is said about Lemurs in Madagascar?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. They are traditionally killed for bush meat.]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. They usually produce offspring every year.]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. They are being affected by the illegal gold mining industry.]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. They were held in high regard by local people.]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="29">
	<Text><![CDATA[Tamara Rojo to be Artistic Director of English National Ballet.  ………………………………Tamara Rojo, prima ballerina at the Royal Ballet, is to become artistic director of English National Ballet. The 37-year-old dancer will take over in September from Wayne Eagling, whose unexpected departure after seven years was recently announced. Rojo, a principal dancer at the Royal Ballet, said she was honored to be taking over at a company she spent three years with in the late 1990s. Rojo takes over in difficult economic times. The English National Ballet, which tours extensively nationally and internationally, has been hit by a 15% but in Arts Council funding. Rojo spent three years with the company after she left Spain in 1996, making a significant splash for performances which prompted the ‘Times’ to call her ‘dance revelation of the year’. After that, she joined the Royal Ballet where her reputation has gone from strength to strength.]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[29. What is said about Tamara Rojo?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. She will be the artistic director of the Royal Ballet]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. She previously danced with the English National Ballet]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. She dance with the Royal Ballet for seven years]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. Funding will increase when she takes over the ballet company]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
<question nquest="30">
	<Text><![CDATA[Cheryl Cole Feared For Her Life on a Plane in Germany.  ………………………………Cheryl Cole says she feared for her life when she got trapped on her private jet during a lightning storm. The singer was at Frankfurt airport in Germany during a tour when lightning struck the runway. Her plane wasn’t allowed to take off and no-one was allowed to leave the aircraft as it was too dangerous. Cheryl was so scared but she thought: “This is it. I’ve got an album to promote and I’ve got so much yet to do.”But she said that thinking about her charity mountain climb in 2009 helped her focus. “I remembered I’d climbed Kilimanjaro, so I took a bit of strength from that.”]]></Text>
	<question1><![CDATA[30. What is said about the singer, Cheryl Cole?]]></question1>
	<answers1>
	<answ1><![CDATA[a. She was in a storm on Kilimanjaro]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[b. Her plane was grounded during a storm]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[c. She refused to fly during a storm]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[d. Her plane flew through a storm]]></answ4>
	</answers1>
	<question2><![CDATA[]]></question2>
	<answers2>
	<answ1><![CDATA[]]></answ1>
	<answ2><![CDATA[]]></answ2>
	<answ3><![CDATA[]]></answ3>
	<answ4><![CDATA[]]></answ4>
	</answers2>
</question>
</exam>
